Welcome to the series of videos on top of Web services in this video we'll start with the basic question
what ease of that Selby's think about it.
What is up that service an application A is sending a request and the web service is responding back
with a response.
Let's consider an example.
OK.
So let's take a Facebook Web site or tweet to say you launch it in the browser.
The browser S.A.G. quest to the twitter is over all the Facebook server and you get to Hajim a response
back and browser around it.
Does that make the Facebook application and the Twitter application of web service or is there more
to it.
The most important thing to understand is the fact that when we talk about Web services there are three
keys three very important things that each were up to we should sell for the web so is this designed
for machine to machine interaction.
When I am visiting Facebook page what I am actually doing is not a machine to machine interaction it's
actually a person visiting a website.
When I go to my shopping portal I'm actually it's basically me a person going and visiting the shopping
website that's the that in those kind of scenarios the server is not really offering of web service
what it's offering is something called a web application for something to be called a web service.
It should support machine to machine interaction.
That's basically application to application interaction.
So for me to be able to call something a web service it should be able to interact with their applications.
So for example this is a new application let's say to do so is then that application should be able
to send a request saying OK get me stuff to do.
And this service should be able to respond back with the respond with a list do.
That's basically.
So it should be able to support application to application interaction.
The second important thing is it should be interoperable.
That is basically it should not be platform dependent.
If I'm offering a web service it should not matter whether the application is built on dot net or built
on Java or built on beach or wherever it is build platform of the client should not matter.
So does any other kind of system should be able to invoke and get the data from the web so is that basically
interoperable.
The only important thing it should love communication all over the network.
The other application might be residing within our network outside the network or on the Internet.
It should not really matter.
So one of the most important things is web services should allow communication with things outside the
boundary of our own system.
These are the three keys for designing you over.
So he says they should be designed for machine to machine interaction.
They should be incorruptible and they should love communication.
Or will it work.
The important question is how can you make your web services drop.
The way we make our web services interoperable that is platform independent is by making our requests
and responses platform independent.
So if you make your request and your response platform independent that's it.
Your website is then will be platform independent because anybody can call you at the request and get
a response back.
So the most popular pop platform independent format for requests and sponsors are examine and be days
on X MLS typically used in case of soap and so on is kind of the most popular format when it comes to
various field services.
So that's basically a quick introduction to what is a web service and how does web service become more
platform independent.
We'll talk more about other services in the next week.
Until then.
Barry.