Well come back in that you will talk about soap is what does this open up to is what is soup or is this
open loop header and body.
Let's get started now.
So what is a sole purpose service.
Let's look at an example.
So we have a two application which is offering services and they are accepting simple request and sending
back a simple example spawns.
Is this a superb service.
Does it become a soap.
So it's actually not for something to be Earth soap so we examine because support it should be called
SOAP XML request and soap.
Excellent response.
So it should be in a specific format called soap.
When we talk about superbe services the most important thing is the format of the exchange.
So how is the request question then how is the response and then what is the format what is the format
that is most important thing.
The format is soap.
Earlier soap used to stand for a simple object access protocol but it's no longer a simple object access
protocol.
So it's no longer an acronym.
It's kind of a simple name which represents this format so substantial for a format where you have soap
and when up when we talk about the soap request or a soap response it should meet these standard.
So you would have a soap and well up inside which there is an optional header and there is a board.
So this is kind of at the high level the structure of your request and the response so that you are
looking at a request or respond.
They allow us open all up inside that you would have a soap header and so bored.
They had that typically contains information meta information like authentication or things like that
authentication authorization things like that and body would contain the real content of the request.
So let's say I want to get this place with court details then probably the body might contain get court
details.
But the court's idea is one if I'm getting to details probably the body would contain get to do the
deed and the idea of the to do I would want to retrieve the detail would most important thing is when
you call something a top but so is it should exchange the request and response in this specific format
as we discussed.
The format is Topix M-L request and supect similar response.
The thing about top is its transport independent.
Have you send the request so does not get about.
So when I call something superb services the transport can either be over the web that is Hashd DP or
it can be or were the MQ so it can.
The message might be even sent across using a queue.
So the way it might be is you might have two applications listening on the queue.
One is the producer.
The other is the consumer and the producer application would be listening on the queue for messages
when theres a new message in the queue.
It looks at it and consider to respond back on the queue.
That basically thought or what and where we are using it.
Q As the transport the other format is top overhead should it be when we are using web as a format when
we are offering soap services on the Internet on the web on the Internet whether we would want to offer
them.
The other thing about top is the service definition has a strict format its called with Dell or do as
deal with Dell web service definition language.
We'll look at it in detail in the subsequent video in this we look at the following question So what
is this soap.
So is anything that added to the soap format and wollop header and body or is soap soap is no longer
an acronym.
It's just something which presents these kind of Apso.
And what is a soap and really it's kind of the encompassing thing for the Scoppetta.
And so what is so peda typically contains the authentication information.
And so a body contains the actual details of the request and the spot and then the next video by.