Welcome back in this way you will start looking at the details of a request and the response we'll look
at examples of a quick withdrawal point and also what is stupider what kind of information to send in
this opener and also we look at an example of Thorpedo.
So let's get started.
As we discussed in the previous We do a super request contains a soap and inside the envelope is a header.
Here we have the Hadad and we have a board and you can see that the name space which is used here is
this top name space.
So SOAP envelope.
This is the named place which we should use when we talk about soaps or schemas or similar but less
so.
So it's like us.
And so this is map which we are using in here.
This open schema and what our specific thing get called Details requests.
We use a customized names so we call it how should we be in when did it not come.
Slash cortices.
So if you see all the things all the elements inside our request they use this too.
That's our namespace that's a custom namespace that we have created so that they will not be any collision
with.
Let's say there are of course other platforms which are offering different kinds of courses.
I don't want there to be one conflict with them.
So I use the namespace to differentiate my requests.
So and this too is here.
So in this to do industry everywhere in tade our request they'll be in a state which is used.
And you can see that the namespace for open loop is so open.
So for head or body all these things which are really related to the soup structure in lollop head a
body the soap and a piece that didn't in-space.
So this is an example so request.
Why isn't this request they get something called a soap press and I get the soap response has the name
spaces as well.
So you would have the soap and will up name space and also you have our customized space and you can
see that we are getting a detailed response back with the detail of the court record ID name description
and all that kind of stuff.
So this is a very simple example of soap request and soap response.
Next we'll look at something called Soap header.
In the previous video we said so Peddar and Bane's authentication information right.
So here we are using W-S.
See that one of the authentication implementations of WSEX security.
So security specifies the security for sope that so uses the standard through a security first approach.
So he says this is one of the implementations of that.
So we use WSC is the security.
So we specify the publicity namespace in here and in the header we send the user name and the password.
So here we are sending the user name and the password.
If we were using digest authentication then we would have been sending the digest instead of the password.
So in addition to the body of the request what we'll do is we'll also send the head.
So the header contains the security information of the request.
In this video we looked at examples of soap request response.
We also look at examples of soap request with a torpedo containing the authentication information until
an extremely boring.