Back in this review we'll talk about WCM.
What is his definition language and what are the different parts of the GST.
This is D-W is the definition of words so we use this if you provide this W-S D-IL to any of the lines
of Web services they'd be able to know every detail of have to call you over.
So these.
So let's not dig in and see what are the different details that are present in the causes.
BSD.
So at the high level the important things that Apple isn't that types.
You have a variety of messages.
Then you have a type of binding and a Silvius and this is how most of the doublings deals would look
like.
This is kind of a common structure among all of these deals the DL types defines this stuff which is
present in this key.
So if I look at the as DL types you you'd see the schema that we have created completely being present
in here.
We are defined the exact details in the request response request and respond.
So this is exactly what is present in W-S deal date.
This is exactly what we defined in our access to the index of the access is actually inside as the date
basically defines what the different structures to similar structures that we are going to use.
The next thing I would define the messages the messages are basically defining the requests and responses.
So what are the different requests and responses that will be that will be changed by the different
operations.
So we might have multiple operations.
And what would be the request and what we did at this point.
So here we are saying okay this is the request and this is actually picking up from the element if I
get all calls details request which is defined in the types in the types we are defining the element
and here we are saying this is something which can be a request or response for one of the operation.
So both the requests and responses we will have messages defined.
So the important thing is here there's a complex staple called detail.
This cannot be used as a request or response element.
The only things which can be used as requests or response elements are what they are mapped as messages.
Once you have that request and response to messages defined you can actually map them to operations.
How do we do that.
We do that by using bolt type support type matches defines all the different operations.
So this particular of them so is pro-white these operations.
What are the options.
Get all Corddry to dance and get court details and in the operation map what does that request and what
is the response you're saying Forget all the details.
The request is get of course the deal's request and the responses get all the details of this bond.
And similarly for the other one for the other one which is good because we did the request is get court
details request and the response is get good details as Bond.
What type is like an interface so you are defining OK this web server is all for these services if you
want to call this web service you would need to pass this input.
And this is the output.
So this is like the interface is different.
How do you call a specific method of right.
So that's exactly what is specified in the pool table type is the interface and the binding defines
the implementation.
How do you really call it.
So here the important thing is that we define our style and the transport the transport defines we're
using hash DTP hash UDP is Internet Web.
So the call to use call or happened or should he be so we are defining soap or what.
GTP.
So what we will be using is the other option obviously is soap or M.
Q When we are going to use q to transfer the requests and response style we are using here is document
to indicate the fact that we are actually exchanging complete Exham requests and similar response.
The alternate deal for document is actually something called RPE C which is the more procedure calls.
Its like calling a procedure which is defined somebody else.
It's like calling a a third which is present somewhere else when all the RTC we would need to define
the input parameters and we need to define the return type just like a third document is the most frequently
used style of so binding.
So here we are using a binding style of document and we are saying we are going to send the request
over which DP We are indicating that these two operations are using this as binding.
So ending defines how are we going to expose our operations guessing we are going to expose them over
which deep deep the last one which is present in here is this is what is the location.
How are the clients going to use this.
So.
So you're saying super dress this is the address at which this is a high level that defines all different
elements may say just define what are the requests and the responses.
They defined the interface.
Basically what are the operations that are available binding maps the operations to how you are exposing
them whether using soap or HTP or soap or MQ and servies maps it to end point.
What is it you are a real bitch symbolist can use to call this web service.
These are the different details that are typically present in all the Dahlia's DNS and then the next
step bullae.