Well come back in this week you will be there.
But what is a contract first approach what is next is the example of access.
So let's start with contract first approach.
What is really a contractures approach.
First what is a contract.
In the earlier video we looked at that as deal right.
Because it was Dell Perhaps that is the definition language versus definition language is something
called a service definition or a contract contract is basically like just like when you do some trade
you have an agreement between the seller and the buyer.
You will have any agreement between the service provider and the service consumer.
So similarly when we talk about Web services we also have a contract here.
The contract specifies what is the format of the request whether it's ex-MIL day or so on what kind
of format do you support.
What is the format of the response.
The second thing which is important is the structure of the request and it spawns the most important
thing is what its transport used it or whether rage over.
Q And how can this service be.
God these are the most important things in U.S. service definition or your contract contract first approach.
What we would do is we would focus on defining the contract at the start of implementing a service.
So when you implement a service you will not directly go and jump in to implement the Java code for
it.
What we do is we first define access D or we try to come up with WS deal.
So we kind of try and define what is the structure of the request what is the structure of the response
what are the transport used and how can a consumer consume ourselves to make.
We create a file defining all these stuff.
When we talk about superciliousness this contract is specified in the 5th it w as the webservices definition
language when it comes to race full web services.
There is no standard really.
So you can use any of the options that we discussed in contract first.
What we do.
We define our contract first and we bring Web services out w SDL that is our contract is defined or
is generated from an excess D.
So what we would do is we would first define Xs D and X is the existing schema definition XML schema
definition.
Lets look at it right.
The it specifies what a valid ex-MIL looks like.
For example here I am saying OK I want to create a get cause details request.
I would want to use the namespace of courses and I would want to have an ID element in it and this can
accept only numbers.
So there is this structure I would want to define for my request example XML schema definition allows
us to define this.
So how do we do that in an example schema definition.
Its very simple.
So we are saying access element name is to get.
Details.
So we are saying I would want to create an element by name get cause details request.
You say this there can be another element we are saying this is a complex state which will have a sequence
of element here had There is only one element.
When we look at the response we'll see that there will be multiple element a sequence of elements and
there is this element with the name ID.
So I would want to have inside the get go details to request an element named ID and said Good God detailed
request.
I would want to have ID.
And what values can it have.
It can only have in DJO values.
So this can only have integer values.
So what we are defining is how our response extremal should look like.
Next let's take the example our first point example.
So here you can look at Get cause details response and inside that we will want to code details with
an ID name and the description.
So let's look how the axes differ that looks like to be find the x is the forget color detail response.
We are saying get details response can names an element of type cost details and we are defining what
is the content of those details separately.
The fact that we are defining the structure of course details separately helps us to use it in Mali
people respond examples.
So this is good cause we didn't respond.
They might be get all cores detailed response where you might be returning a list of these kind of quarterly
deals.
So if I defined the code details separately how can we use the multiple.
So let's see how that looks like.
So when I define the code details and think this is a complex type which is a sequence sequence of thought
allow an ID which is an integer I'll have a name which is Thring and a description which is also a string.
So I'm saying there would be id name and description inside because it tells Elby ID name and description
that's exactly what.
We are also defining that X is the when we develop so we use this with playing with services.
What we would do is we would define the entire X as the first and bring up services would provide us
a feature wherein you can generate your dabblings DL out of this SSD and you can change that Abdias
deal to your customers.
This approach of creating the X is the first that's basically creating a WS.
The first is called Contract first approach.
We are defining the contract.
Your response looks like how you have to request looks like and all that kind of stuff before we actually
get into the implementation of this is in this short.
We look at what is a contract or what is it.
So it is definition.
We did what is a contract first approach.
What is ethics is the end we look up at a couple of examples of existing snippets and then the next
we do it by.