Come back in this Would you like to focus on something called Jacques's b a b for example binding.
What is a Jacques's B and how you can configure a Jacques's plugin.
In the earlier with you we talked about the fact that when you're developing of servies you define the
X as the first really find the ex-MIL schema definition for us.
I mean this is obviously when we a developing something with spinning Web services Springboro Services
uses a contract first approach.
So we defined X as degenerate as deal out of it and then implement the end point out to do application
will accept a SOAP XML request and we'll send Sobig similar response.
So the input is excisemen the output is as simple as well but true application is job application.
Right.
So the SML needs to be converted to Java and the Java object needs to be converted into a similar response
as well.
So how does this happen.
This is called binding.
So this SML request needs to be bound to a Java object and the Java object needs to be bound and any
XML response needs to be generated from this Java API.
For example binding defines a specification for how to do that kind of conversion.
So a Java API for example binding defines what you can actually do X Imelda Jawa and to X similar kind
of condition.
Let's consider another example.
So here is the code details that we defined earlier.
So we defined a complex type called cause details in our End Point what we would need to be able to
do is to take our Jawa object and generate an example of this structure with the name and description.
What we would need to do is we would need to be able to take out a jar jar object duelists from it and
set it into an example.
The job or EPA for example binding pro-white a simple plugin which would allow us to generate Java objects
of this definition.
So what we can do is from this access the we can generate Java objects matching exactly this structure.
So if you look at this example which is present in here we have a package called Come in 28 minutes
courses where we have all the detail.
Now in the courses there's a cause details but Jawa if you look at this code details that Jawa it contains
the exact structure that we have defined in X as the called the date Id name and description.
So what happens is if I create an instance of Corddry days and set the values into this new Jacques's
b we'll be able to generate X out of this.
Now how do I generate this Jowler file.
I don't want to write this kind of stuff by hand right.
If I want to actually have a structure of this and I have to write another out class which contains
the exact structure.
It's a lot of effort to maintain that.
Right so what we do is we use something called the X B plugin the Jaggs we Plug-In what it does is it
takes schemas as the input.
It can understand the as the schema and it can generate the jobs or objects for that.
What it does it takes record details that acts as the as the input and it generates all these files.
So you can see that there is a get or get all cause details request get cause details requests.
So the get calls didn't request here has a corresponding get called Details request.
And you if you look at the structure it would exactly match whatever structure we have defined in all
the Jawa objects are actually generated by the tanks be plugged in for the jacks be plug in.
What we are using is something called Jacks.
To me when plugging this is configured in your project Maimon bombardment.
And if you look at it we are using 1.6 worship and the input for that is the access.
So wherever we are operating the access the output makes his deep into its main resources.
So we have that as the input output is the Java code.
So where do we put our show.
So in this we do believe that what is Jacques's be and how we can configure a Jacques's people plugin
to be able to convert our access into Java objects in the next with you will look at how to make use
of the objects which are generated by DXP and set values into them and point and in the next release.