Welcome to the studio where we're going to talk about what is important and let's look at a sample example
and point it in with spinning Web services.
So what is an end point.
Or do web services do they accept request and tenderers want back that that's exactly what and putting
this end point accept a request and does all the business logic you'd need.
Or it might not do all the business logic you'd need it would call another service to do all the business
logic and it would come with the rest boards back into the structure so that I can send to XM back toward
an end point.
Let's look at an example.
This is the process code details that request what we're doing in here is for a specific request ID
we want to get the details of the course and return them back.
If you look at the payload route it defined what kind of quest this end point can handle what we are
saying is any request with the namespace of this and the local for pipe as get cause details requests.
Then you can map it to this specific method and what we are also adding in is to get those details to
request.
So this is good cost diddles request is generated by Jacques's B.
This is the one which is present in here.
This is generated by Jacksboro get court details request and we take the request from the because we
take the ID and then we get the details.
Once we have the details of the court we would now map this code into the code details mapping structure.
What we are doing in the map call detail method is declaring an instance of the code detail.
This is the ex-inmate.
This is the one which is generated with DXP.
So we are creating an instance of that and taking the values from the quartz object and setting them
into the.
Details in the map code details method.
We are actually taking the values from a business object and setting it into the SML object.
So we are taking the values from our beans and setting them into the beans which are generated by be.
So these are all the Jacques's be things that we are setting us into so discours detail as we Lubet
live is the Jacques's beating this is generated by that people again that pre-configured earlier.
So in the end point what we are doing is actually taking that request or from the request we are taking
the details that are important.
We are calling this service to get all the details in the business objects from the business objects
we need to map it into the ex-MIL objects because we need to send the similar response so the map post
details maps that and we are returning that specific thing back and to make sure that the quest is mapped
properly.
We are using it in addition call request payload whatever data is part of this request really get mabbe
bound to this request and whatever details we are sending back will be the response payload the SML
will be bound to the Java object and the Java object would be converted to examine and the response
would be sent back.
Basically the end point is accepting an external input.
It cannot sit in Java takes it processes that take the response object convert it into ex-MIL and send
it back to the response great in this way we looked at it as an end point and we looked at an example
in point which was written using spinning web services and in the next video were.