In this way you will look at very important concept with being Web Services which is message dispatcher.
What is the message especially servlet and how do we can figure is better service.
When we talk about web applications we know about dispatch celebrate the spaceship's tablet acts as
the front controller.
It makes sure that all the requests first go to the dispatcher so late and then they would be distributed
out to the Carrack controllers.
When it comes to spring services message dispatch or service that does exactly the same thing.
So what it does is the first request goes to message especially servlet and then it looks at the quest
it looks at the name space.
It looks at the request details and then mapped it to the appropriate and appointment.
In the previous example reconfigured and in point M.Tech we said this is the method which should be
called when the local part is get called Details request.
So dispatcher established knows all this stuff so it knows that the name space.
This local by this maps to this method.
So when the dispatcher Sublette gets get calls vitis request it would map that request and called.
This is if we meant that how do we configure the method special so let it.
Very simple.
What we are looking at is the java configuration for that.
So the most important thing is the message the special service that is actually served.
So we need to first configure a serve lead for that.
So we need to do something QAL so late registration been inspiring if you would want to configure us
of let you would use a service registration been several registration been accepted to input most important
inputs that tablet registration been accept is disserve lit and also the you are right this is late
and this is the way we are mapping to that place to fix it and to configure the message itself.
All we need is an application context so we are taking the application context and we are setting it
as the application context or here.
And we are defining it as being we are defining this as the spring.
I mean this is basically a simple definition for message dispatch.
So we are saying all the requests which comes to W-S that need to be processed by the message dispatches.
In this video we took a quick look at message especially Sylhet and how you can configure it in a Java
configuration.