Welcome back in the previous steps we talked about the fact that when we use screengrab Sousa's we tried
the Xs and generator ideas deal out of it.
So how do we configure generation of AWOS DL when we are using spring but services that's what we are
going to look at right now.
One of the important things that we need to know is the fact that what is the input so the input generated
here is the schema right to disclose details that exist the schema.
So the access to which we wrote and look that in the earlier examples.
So this is the starting point for generating the BSD Doubler's deal will be generated using the access.
DS So what we're defining is Access does Kema.
This is an buy into this is a spring been using a glass bottle of sorts.
We are actually trying to look at because details are as they are not class but and using a simple Access
schema to define this specific things.
Now what we have this define we would want to now define the WC we'd be using the SDL 1.1.
So we're using default as the one one definition that the class which we are making use of.
You can see that one of the arguments which I posit is this is this.
That's basically what I would access the schema which we are defining in here.
And to be able to define a dabblings DL You need to define a pool type in the earlier video we looked
at what is a pool type put papers like an interface.
So we are defending code for sport as the pool type for it and also the name space is what we already
discussed.
Other than that we need to set v w d ill will be available so be warned of the WMD.
So we are saying this Doubler's deal should be available at slash W-S.
So what happens is when you launch up a sporting context the spring framework would look at this configuration
looks at the code schema and define a WS deal.
And you can see the damages exposed as we saw in the previous step in this quick review.
We looked at how to generate that GSD using webservices.