Welcome back in this way let's look at how you implement error handling for services services and what
is in store for it.
One of the most important things with any web service is that when an error happens you do want to give
a character respond back to the customer.
So who is calling your service.
Where is your client you would want to give him the appropriate response.
If the service fails and you don't send anything back then the client does not know what to do.
So with up any service we need to provide an error response stating exactly what went wrong so that
they can take the corrective action.
And so pooled is this structure in which contained an error response back.
Let's look at examples for that.
The great thing about tippling Web services is the fact that it provides a good deal for error handling.
So if in the end point here we are trying of course smartphone's exception so from sending in I.T. which
is like not existing So let's say I'm sitting in thousand or 10000 for a course which does not exist
in our database.
What would happen is by default billing services would look at these exceptions so we are trying of
course not found exception.
So it knows that.
So it handles it and it turns this slope faultless bones back.
But when we look at the details of this are faultless and it's into a full court of soap and we're in
the search word.
And it says Invalid court ID thousand.
What we are doing is we are trying a new course not funny exception to it saying well good phone with
requests or Gidday.
So when I send a request for ID towels and the cause does not exist I'm going to go so far this is good.
So by default I can see that being webservices is doing a good job at providing a good soap in the fall.
But this can be for that improved things here you're saying fault code is so up and up so what.
There's not really a server fault right.
So the client is actually requesting for invalid code.
Whose fault it is.
It should be the client who is at fault.
What what other things I can do is actually SAY fault code not aligned so I can define an act so poorly.
In addition on the course not found exceptions on the court not an exception and defending an edge.
So Paula in addition you can say fault code is equal fault code but client then what would happen in
default court would appear as if it so.
And Will Cain and also spring webservices provides you an option to define a custom filed court as well.
So here I am saying follow court is custom for court and I'm defining a namespace space and an ID for
a default call.
So if you are solid with documentation you can put documentation thing when this is the rule which comes
back then.
This is what you should do.
So you can actually define both custom code and also you can use specific quotes as well if you do this
if you use this kind of force structure.
Then the response you would get back is Falconis course not fun.
So we are seeing specific for the court to we I think Falconis 0 0 1 not phone and the text is invalid.
Court ID in the short we do we looked at how to implement data handling for your soap.
So he says and what is so important and then the next when you re.