Welcome back in this we do really address the most important basic questions which are related to spring.
We'll look at the big picture of spring a little later we'll talk about touring model spring projects
and things like that and also understanding why spring is popular.
We'll handle all those kind of questions a little later when we have a good understanding of spring.
Let's start with the most basic things about spring like when we talk about spring we talk about loose
coupling we say spring enables us to develop loosely coupled applications without dipping into injection.
We talk about being in motion of control and also we talk about the wedding.
This is the set of concepts that we'll try and get into in this space.
So the question is which we are going to talk about are things like what is loose coupling How do you
make an application usually coupled and also talk about something like what is dependency what is dependency
injection and what is or you'll see.
And that question of control.
And also we look at a few examples or dependency injection and auto wiring.
Let's get started now.
Let's start with loose coupling.
Let's look at the example for tight coupling.
So this do business so is here is dependent on something called to do that well.
So when you look at any application you have a business layer which needs the data.
So here to do business so is the business leader.
And to date this is part of the data earlier.
So this business with component needs data from this data service company and what it doing here is
it's directly creating an instance of this to do business service is directly creating an instance of
d to do data services.
Let's consider another example.
These are complex and we got it on my MP.
Let's say there is a very complex algorithm that you are implementing and as part of it it needs some
sorting what it does here is directly create an instance of the bubble top.
God damn this is tight coupling because this complex algorithm I am bill is now tightly coupled to bubble
sart algorithm.
So let's say tomorrow you would want to switch from bubble start to peak start for this complex algorithm.
It would be difficult because you need to actually make the change in here.
You have to change the implementation you have to change the code and everything in here.
This is called tight coupling tight coupling is basically where your competition is tightly coupled
to the dependency.
So this bubble sort of got written.
So the complex algorithm needs the bubble sort and got them to be able to do its work.
However if you want to change discard them to something then it will be difficult.
This is what is called type coupling.
So how do you break this coupling that with loose coupling come into picture.
So what we would do is ensure of tightly coupling the business service to the data as it is in what
we do is we create an interface to clearly an interface called to do that.
So is it just having a metal calorically to do this and instead of doing an instance with the will of
the we we're creating an instance of the interface.
And also we don't create an instance of it here.
What we do is we provide a hand track.
So what we are saying is OK what is using the to do business is can provide an implementation of that
to do that as always.
Who wants to make use of the to do business so is we're saying OK you can create an instance of the
do do business service but make sure that you decide what implementation of the do data is to use.
This is much more flexible.
Let's consider another example.
Oh here we have B-complex and brought it to my MP which is using Sawtell got written out.
So what we have done is instead of hard coding the bubble sort of them we said okay we don't want to
hard code we don't want it tightly coupled with bubbletop.
Got it.
What we did is we created an interface called sart you got it them.
So they thought got it has one Materne site and we have two implementations of this are garden.
We've started our bubble certainly got them.
Now what happens here.
The complex algorithm I am building makes use of the interface sort algorithm.
In addition here we can provide a constructor.
So who wants to use the complex algorithm and people can either create an instance of the quixotry don't
read them or create an instance of the bubble sort algorithm and pass it to the complex and read them
constructor to create it.
That what is called loose coupling loose coupling is where you are.
Code is not tightly coupled it's not directly dependent on its dependencies.
Let's now move onto the next question.
What is a dependency in the loose coupling example.
We look at the true business so we need to do that as Tobys.
So the business service is dependent this dataset is complex you I my MP in need.
This article got written so complex I'll go to my MP is dependent on this sort all the time.
When we look at typical job application architectures you have multiple layers of Webley business leader
and Tellier the business leader component are typically dependent on the data layer and the web layer
components are typically dependent on the base business.
So typically when we call a dependency it is something which another class is dependent on to provide
it.
So these complex algorithms to pro-white the service of its algorithm.
It needs a dependency called sart you got it.
I'm so sorry I got it.
You said dependency of the complex al-Qadi atom the data layer might need a connection to the database
or it might need something like a DBC template to execute the query so the detail here is dependent
on JEDEC template to JTB template is a dependency for most of the components which are present in the
detail.
Now what is dependency injection.
What we would need to do typically is when I want to create an instance of the complex algorithm I am
Bill I need to use the constrictors Altaic new complex algorithm I am people of yours quicksort algorithm.
So here I am creating an instance of the quicksort algorithm and taking it and by adding it and creating
another instance of the complex algorithm I am also here and creating different beans by myself how
I work with spring when we say component Edwar are wired and things like that.
These things are done automatically by spring what does spring do spring sees that there is an add or
the word annotation in here.
So as soon as it finds the quick search algorithm what it does is it would auto wire it in here.
So when it's creating the brain for complex algorithm I am Bill it.
Or to wire the bean off sorry you them.
This is what is called dependency injection.
So what does it it's just for the beams and then finds the appropriate bin and or wire it in here.
This is called dependency injection dependency injection is basically the process where spring framework
looks for the beans it starts searching for the beans identifies the dependencies and creates the instances
of beans and auto Weyers them in.
So when you use Spring Framework we don't write code like this all this kind of stuff is done by the
printing frame but this is what is called dependency injection concept or the term which is frequently
used is in question of control.
Rate what is in question of control.
So in the complex algorithm I impalement the first implementation of it which was having data coupling
had new bubble start algorithm.
So this is tightly coupled also who is taking the responsibility of creating the instance of bubbletop
terrorism.
It's the complex I'll go into my NPL class itself so that the complex algorithm I imperial class is
creating an instance of the bubble sort.
Got it.
So who has the control.
The control is with complex algorithm.
I am however in the local version of it.
What we do is say complexity of my Ambien you would put a thought algorithm as a of Wired.
And we don't really create an instance of it here.
Who digs the control of creating the instance the control of creating the instance of complex algorithm
I am Bill goes to the class which is using it or it goes to the framework it goes to the spring framework.
The spring framework would now be taking control and it would inject the dependency of Tardelli got
them in the spring they would search for the beans and it would inject the dependencies in.
So this is why it is called inversion of control so the control which was with the class because it
was taking the control early the complex regarding my impaled was in control earlier but now we are
shifting the current control to the users of the complex.
One of them I am Bill or we are shifting the control to the dependency injection framework.
This is what is called inversion of control.
Actually if you look at all this concept the notion of control deepend injection loose coupling coupling
all of them are really related to each other.
That's why we thought it is best to have one example and look at it in the tank in relation with all
these important concepts.
Now the last thing that we want to discuss is again what these are wiring when I put an end station
call at Oughterard in here Spring Framework needs to find this dependences art them.
I mean needs to find a bean which would match this dependency in here and it would need to populate
the dependency in this process is called auto wiring.
We discuss a lot about our the wiring in the subsequent readers here.
We just want to introduce you to the concept of art or wiring in the street.
We do.
We looked at the different concepts that are really important related to spring.
We took one example and we use this same example to illustrate all these things and build the next video.