In the class we do believe the basic concepts of spring and this we will look at something called Music
second data.
We'll talk about different don't like being in fact the application context and look at how we can create
application context.
So let's get started.
What are the important roles of and I will and then the most important tools of the container are to
find the beams to be able to wire the dependencies find the means identify their dependencies and find
the dependencies in and also to manage the lifecycle of the bean.
That is basically creating the instances of the bean and all the processing the lifecycle event and
making sure that the bean is destroyed after complete.
Those are the important ones.
Let's take an example for example over here we're actually seeing a component on the complex and got
my MP and we are seeing it all the wired on this go at them.
And also at component on the we've certainly got them what the container needs to do is it needs to
identify that there is at component on these two things it says.
So a lot of them and complex a lot of them my unpeel are the components I would want to manage.
These are the beings I need to create.
That's number one.
I didn't think what are the important components identifying the beans.
So that's the step one.
The second step is to wire dependencies.
So I would need to also identify the dependencies so it need to understand complexity about them I need
to sort out you got it them.
So I would need to create an instant only to create a bean.
I would need to find a be in for the start algorithm.
What does the IOC contain it.
It will then go and search for that particular in to it first identify the bins and create instances
of those things which do not have any dependencies or quicksort them does not have any dependencies
so it creates an instance of it.
And then comes here and sees that OK.
This one needs the start and go get them to order why is it in here.
So it will make the Tarlton go to them I will able to decompress then go to my MP and create a bean
or feed as well.
The important role of an I was to contain it are to find the means to find its dependencies and make
sure that the beans are wired in and also to make sure that all the lights actually went off or been
of them creation life cycle you end and destroy.
We typically use two terms when it comes to IOC containers in putting the two terms which are related
to music and in our application context.
And in fact the Bean Factory is the most basic question of the U.S. container that putting pro-white
being factory the basic things off NORC container.
It will be able to do that too.
It will be able to find the beans it will be able to do the dependencies it will be able to manage the
lifecycle movements of the mean that basically what in fact is good it been factory does the basic things
that any AOC container should be able to do that's it.
Nothing more nothing less.
So what is application context application context is under the IOC container.
Howard The thing is this is much more advanced kind of I use the container.
It is almost something you can call us.
In fact we place Spillers to what you have been factory has pro-white all these features.
And in addition what it does is provide things like AOP like as petroleum.
Programming is one of the important things we discuss later.
So it provides all the features that we would discuss in the aspect oriented programming part and it
provides internationalization capabilities as well to things like misstates sources and things like
that.
We'll talk about internationalization a little later as well.
And the other thing which it provides is the web application context feature when we talk about web
applications that things like request session and there is a request scope in scope and other scopes
which come into picture so support for all of them is what is provided by application contex been factory
provides the basic features application context is being replaced plus and it provides all the features
like features internationalization web application context features on top of being fact will be the
important role of an eye with the container will be in fact application context.
And we compared been fatly with the application context as well.
And most importantly you need to remember is in most of the circumstances putting recommends you to
use an application.
So in most of the applications youll always go with application context because you would need features
like internationalization.
You need to be able to create a web application context and things like that.
However you would want to go with the Bean Factory only when you are in severe memory constrained.
You don't want to use a lot of memory in your application in those kind of situations so you would go
with something called a Bean Factory.
Most of the applications I really work with all of them use an application context.
Next we would want to discuss how to create an application context with spring creating an application
context with really really simple you can actually define the context in two ways.
Either you can define it using an example or you can define it using annotation called a configuration
to instead being there isn't an addition call at configuration but you can use to define an application
context configuration as well.
So the configuration for the application context you can actually define using XML or you can define
using Java.
So these are the two options which are reliable.
We look at them in detail a little later as well.
So once you have that configuration you can create the application context using something like classpath
example application context what this does is it looks for all these ex-inmate So it looks for these
examiners.
Where does it look for in the class but just by the simple application context is one of the ways of
creating an application context using XM.
Here we are providing an area of application context file that as the input to the construct of this
particular piece the other way is to use the Java configuration.
So the spin context of the Java configuration and we can create an application context for that using
an end iteration config application context.
You can also create an application context in your uniters writer in your unit that you would want to
launch an application context quickly.
And this kind of situations we can use something called a spring you need for class runner to alter
another called Spring runner.
So he's been in it for class run is the same as being crammed like enough so you can actually add run
with a station in your unit test on the green run a class and you can specify either your job or configuration.
This is our test context configuration.
So this is a job configuration that you would want to run as part of this disk.
Or you can specify your exim configuration.
So whether you're using a similar configuration or you're using a Java configuration you'll be able
to easily use them in your typical Java code as well as in your unit.
Yes.
In this way you would clearly view the concepts of files contain or will it be in fact an application
context and we understood how to create an application context.
It's spring.
I didn't think it would away.