Really come back in this area you will focus on the questions which are related to component.
So we'll talk about questions like How does spring know where to search for components or beyond what
these components can and how can you define components and similar angelic configurations as well as
how these components can work with springboard actually components.
And it's one of the most important features which is present in spring.
You the applications we define all the beans that we would want to bring to really great I would say
better than my MP and put in a component on it which certainly read them and put an ad component on
it to say this is something which needs to manage more than might be in multiple packages and multiple
places where these components might be defined.
If sprinklers to search every package which is there for component and that will be a big performance
impact.
We need to help spring find where our components are really.
We define our beans.
We would need to help spring identified that what we do is we'll specify Okay spring go in look in business
back gauge going look in data we stub back gate.
These are the packages where beans are defined and that is what is called a component gain competence
can is basically a search Springers for component input for that search packages.
So you would say I'm looking for Package A B C D E F and would go there and search for the components.
So actually spring does not know we have to search for components or beans you need to delicto you need
to.
Okay.
This is the package where I have my components in and what is components can scan is basically the process
where spring looks for these beans and how do you define competence in the molecular configurations.
This is how you do that in a Java configuration.
So in a Jallow configuration you can have an iteration called component again.
So you can to add components and space for all the packages that you want to scan for here and bring
two packages.
Business service and data service you can pay if they come in.
When did mid-stroke bring and scanned the entire thing as well.
You need to decide whether you want to speak or you would want to be generic with your components again.
The other way to define your competence is in an exam or here we're actually using something called
context components.
And we are spacewalking one package and here's what we're saying.
I want a search coming queen Eden example for all the components.
This is an experimental configuration for component.
The last question we want to talk about is how is it done with springboard.
We talk a lot about being a little bit as well if this is a little difficult for you to understand that's
not a problem at all.
We'll discuss a lot more about Buddha a little later but all here we just wanted to talk a little bit
about components can springboard so into being both.
We use an animation called a spring board application.
I think you'd be using an analytical at Springwood application to create your job application or you
would use and in addition call it spring board.
Best to say that this is a unit test related to spring board.
What both these allegations do is they would automatically initiate a component scan on the package
where they are in so at being good application if you put this in addition in any class then which package
it is in.
So he had it in the package being in five steps.
So this package is automatically scanned for component.
And similarly here the test is sping good test emendation is used on this particular test which is in
package common.
We did manage to bring Bates expiring in payslips.
So this package is also scanned for component.
So we springboard when we use this and a patient there's an automatic component and triggered on that
base package where the application class or the application.
Yes I'd be fine.
That's the reason why you would see that most of this spring would applications don't even need to declare
the components again.
As long as you are using this package and it's some package yes.
So if you are putting all your components in this are packages of dispersive package then you don't
have a problem at all that kind of stuff would be automatically scanned and recognized as components
in this way be focused on components we like to understand how spring searches we read how we can space
where components can index Milingo up on figuration and how companies can can be done with spring.
But until we do we're way.