WELCOME BACK IN THIS WOULD YOU would want to focus on what's the difference between controller and component
at repository at ease.
And these kind of annotations in the spring we already used that company in Ottawa and editions right.
What does that component signify.
It signifies the fact that something is a bean that needs to be managed by spring.
If I put that component on something then I'm telling.
OK.
When you are in control of this bin you create this being you would fire the dependencies in you take
care of destroying the been at a later point in time as well.
So that's what that company Insigne face right.
And the word is all about finding the matching being on a dependency over that water wired.
And what do you expect sprint to do.
You would expect to find a matching dependency and or to wire it in.
These are things which we have been discussing a lot in the business with us as well.
Now let's come into the most important part of this do.
That's the difference between a component repository at servies and controller at the high level when
we look at component components the most in reconstruction.
What direct deposit rate is in that controller.
Let's look at it in detail.
When we talk about web applications we talk about multiple layers right.
You have a badly or you have a business layer and a detail.
You can use that component on any of the components in any of these.
So it's really generic.
However when it comes to the other ones at controller for example it's typically used in the babbly
or at comptroller's signifies something which is using the MVC pattern model.
You can pull apart.
And that in the bably or at repository on the other hand specify something on the data that you would
use at repository typically on things like a DA or Data Access object.
So these are the things which are really related to getting the data from your database whether it's
relational database or whether it's a big data data stored.
It doesn't really matter.
So whatever data stored you're talking to you would use that repository on top of it.
The last one we use is typically used in the business layered in your business logic.
The most important functional that you would want to provide is transaction management or you are farside
objects which are present in the business layer you would use at servies There is also a little bit
of meaning which is attached to these annotations by spring and work as well.
So when you tag any component with any repository spring would automatically add the exception translation
for J.D. B.C exceptions.
So whenever a JBC exception happens then it needs to be translated into the specifics pring exception.
So if you put a repository on top of any component then that happens automatically.
And we look at controller a lot more.
When we talk about the MVC What does it signify what is the output What's the input and controller and
things like that.
In summary at component is the most generic one and a repository.
So we as a controller are supposed to be used in it specifically.
It kind of provides an additional way you can classify your components and identified them if you want
to add any specific functionality for that specifically.
So if you want to let's say log all the input and output that are going from your data access method
then you can look at any repository as a way to identify your beans and weave your EPA around them in
3D.
We looked at at component at Waterworld and we also looked at the differences between controller at
component and repository and at civies and additions and then the next video.