This would you would want to look at the different options which are present for spring application
context from an NGO and how do you choose between them in a way we have actually discussed this in one
of the earlier videos as well.
So this might be a little bit of repetition but the important thing we would also want to discuss is
how do you choose between similar configurations.
Also we think this is an important concept so let's discuss it one more time.
Let's look at the example of configuring your application contex right to.
As we look earlier to define the ex-American text with all your being and so in here you'll find all
your beans between your beans and beans.
You define all the beans that you would want to define and you can launch it using class public example
application context so in your main method you can do this and it would try and find this business application
context direct XML and other A or text in the entire class part of your job application.
The job of creating a spin context is also very simple.
You just need to put the configuration on your configuration being you can use beans to define all the
configuration which is present in here and you can launch it up using an addition configured obligacion
context or that you need to do is send the class name that class.
So these are the two with a Java and X-amount Which one do you prefer.
Actually with things like auto wiring and things like component at what the wide and the prominence
of the use of water and it isn't the amount of configuration which we actually put I did not examine
our individual is very minimal.
And I talk when I talk about a big spring application probably I'm talking about some hundred and fifty
lines of x in the configuration or something like hundred lines of Chamba contribution.
What are we talking about is quite a minimal thing so it's not really as important decision to make
as it was before the use of annotations before the use of annotations.
We had to write big big spring application context exemplified.
So you have to define the beans define the dependencies.
Fire them in all that work you have to do that in the economy.
But with all the wild and things like that you don't really need to do that to the amount of population
that we do in Africa or our configuration is very very less.
Actually there is very little to choose so whether you'd want to do the job configuration or similar
configuration you're good to go.
You can actually use either of them.
I don't really have a preference among them but would springboard and springboard having this awesome
annotation at Springwood an allegation and it automatically launching the context up as soon as I put
a configuration on something it would be picked up as spring configuration.
If I have to use SML with sping boot then I have to do a little bit more configuration.
So I prefer not the Jabo configuration especially in spring boot applications because I don't really
need to do any configuration at all all that I need to do is put that configuration on a bean.
Where did this spring configuration.
Then it gets picked up automatically.
If you can you're just being good.
And this was not clear to you.
That's not a problem at all.
We'll discuss that a little more when we talk about tippling boot in one of our subsequent sections.
For now the important thing is there is hardly anything to choose between assembling our configuration
except when it comes to being good applications where Jaba configurations are going to get picked up
and I have a preference for using our configuration.
And then the next step.