Well come back in this.
Let's discuss about but have you read the book problems that Spring Framework.
How do you solve problems such as no unique bean definition exception no such bean definition exception.
And also to understand what are the options you have with at primary and if you get started now look
at this exam.
I have a complex algorithm I am bill which is declared as complaining and sort them out or are wired
on here but there is no component on both quicksort and bubbles sorted as well.
Quicksort algorithm and bubble totally got them do not have a component on them.
When spring searches for some bean which matches this dependency it will not be able to find anything
because there is no ET component on these two bins.
These are not being been any more because they don't have a component on them.
So in these kinds of scenarios what does it throws up.
No such bean definition exception.
So it is.
I want to find implementation of this art.
Everybody them but I'm not able to find it.
It says I'm satisfied dependency to feel sorry you got it.
I'm not qualifying being of this type is every liberal.
It is expected at least one being which qualifies that are to wire a candidate.
So it says I'm trying to find something to order wire in here but there is nothing found actually in
some situations you might really have a component on here so there is a component on quicksort a lot
of them but still spring might not be able to find it.
If you have not defined the component scan Well this is in package X and this is in package Y and you
are scanning only package X for component.
What would happen.
Spring will not be able to find quicksort algorithm because it's in package white which is a different
package from Aix.
When you find yourself handling something like no matching component or no such bean definition exception.
Or you'd see something of this kind no qualifying being of this type available.
Typically the problem would be that I would not put a component on something or you would not put a
component or one of those related annotations.
You should have either a component repository at ease or a control or one of those annotations should
be on your suppling beans and the second problem might be with your component and definition.
If a bean is not part of the component and if this is in a package why and why is not being scanned
for component.
Then spring will not be able to find these beans.
So we know you'll find this exception.
Those are the two prominent reasons.
The reasons are either the component or those related.
In addition to missing or component can is not really defined properly either.
End of the problem is two matching components that is more than one matching component.
So sort them.
Now there are two implementations of that sort.
And Babel certainly taught them what should sping do in that case.
Here you see that there is a wide and there are two component.
Let's say all these classes are in the components and they are all being scanned.
So spring finds two components for the same thing and it tries to match by name.
Sorry to read them.
It seems none of the beans are also match by name.
So what does spinning do.
Throws an exception.
It says Feel start and got them in.
This requires a single bean but actually two are found it is bubble toward the bottom and quicksort
them I'm searching for one.
But actually I'm finding too in this kind of situations spring throws.
You need bean definition exception to it.
I'm not able to find a unique definition.
I'm finding two more than one bean definition and I've not been able to match one correctly.
So how do you solve these kind of problems.
Well the option to which we look at is by naming it properly so here if I want to use Cwiek certainly
go read them.
I recall the instance name quicksort algorithm or bubbles or tell them that using or dividing by name.
The other options which are present are to use something called primary so you can say bubbletop it
is my primary algorithm.
If there are multiple instances of sordidly goaded them in the component scan then bubbles is the primary
one.
So now what does.
It will start using bubble sort algorithm to execute the complex algorithm I am b.
The other option is by using qualifier on the dependency in addition to the auto wide we put something
called a qualifier and give it a name.
Same thing.
The qualifier is main.
You gotta eat them so your bean has this qualifier on it.
It them no has made them qualifier on it.
So it should have been has that qualifier on it.
It will be ought the way in.
So there are basically three options when you have multiple dependencies on the class that are in the
components can actually.
So if you have more than one dependency on the components and but then you can either use the name to
differentiate them so instead of falling sort them you would call it quicksort or the bubble sort and
guarded them so that the matching can happen by name.
If you can do it by name you have the option to do it by putting an ad but Amory going to get one of
you or anybody it is the primary encoded them for them.
That becomes the most important one.
And the other option is to use a qualifier just by putting a word with a specific name and also using
that qualifier on you are beyond definition.
And this we do we looked at some of the problems you might be facing with Spring Framework with respect
to component again and finding the beans and by adding them in.
And we talked about using primary and qualifier and iterations to solve those problems and then the
next with you.
All right.