We'll come back and this we do we would be talking about C D.
Contex and dependency injection we all understand what is context and dependency injection and also
does sibling support conduct's and dependence injection and also which is that a recommended approach
to use TDA or spring annotations.
So what is context and dependency injection what a CD it Cydia is basically a dependency injection standard
for Jawa.
Just like J-P it is standard for defining your Jawa persistence and the patient or JPT find few annotations
and a few interfaces which you can use to implement your object relational mapping.
Similar to that CDA defines API for dealing with dependency injection bring is one of the most popular
Dependency Injection framework and J.Y. eat dependency injection standard Gere's that 3 3 0 creates
this new thing called CD contex dependency injection which is kind of the EPA for how spraying should
work.
However it uses different annotations compared to what spring uses.
For example what we call it auto wired in spring is actually inject in.
What we call it component is named in CDI and Singleton is what is used to define a scope of thing that
is done.
So in terms of the meaning it almost does seem so when I say it inject in CDA it means I would want
to Arto I have something in here when I say it named it means I'm defining I would want the context
dependency injection framework to manage this bean.
This is like a component.
And when I say something is a tingle then then it means there will be only one instance of that specific
thing for application context or instance of the I use the container actually.
When you look at spring spring supports most of this stuff that CDA but are white.
So in shofer at other word you can easily use at inject and instead of at component you can use Nemed
and to define the scope of Singleton it's actually difficult.
But if you really want to go ahead and do that you can say at Singleton as well.
Bring support.
Most of the CDA annotations what is Syria.
Syria is just a simple API for doing dependency injection.
It kind of tries to standardize dependency injection.
Been support CDA.
Yes it's been does support most of the annotations which hopeless and NZD and which one do you recommend
to use TDA or spring and it isn't actually that really really tough question.
If you look at CDA it's a standard.
So it's a standard and that's very cool right.
You always want to go by the standard.
So from that perspective you might want to pick and adapt CDA annotations in your applications.
However what I've seen in my experience of last 15 years is spring always stays one step ahead.
Whenever there's a new feature the highest probability is that you'd find it inspiring first and then
it comes into Java.
The choice is between a standard was this an implementation which is a little bit ahead.
I don't think there is one very clear choice in here.
I think you would not go wrong with either of these choices in this way we look at CDA and also we talk
about how is putting support CDA and also how do you make the choice between TDA and suppling until
the next review.