This would you let's focus on the major features in different Bush of spring.
So we'll look at from the first few versions of spring.
What are the features in each of those versions and also what are the new features in spring for and
spring.
Let's get started now.
So if you look at the version of Spring Framework where there was some very big change for me being
2.5 was the first one because before 2.5 there was no support for annotations there was no at waterwise
there was no ET component or there was no ad controller or any of that kind of stuff.
So there were no annotations which were present in the earlier versions of spring and all the wiring
had to be done by hand.
So if I have to define a been in the X-Men I have to defend that bean.
I have to define the dependencies and Bleier them in and it was a really tough world to program in.
You need that idea of code and parallel to that you would have a thousand lines big.
And that was very difficult to maintain.
And for me 2.5 was a major spring revision because it brought in and the patient and it brought in the
support for that component at auto wide and things like that spring 3.0 was the first question of spring
which made use of the Java five improvements in the language.
I brought in a lot of improvements right along with an additions for loops and things like that.
So I think that he made use of those annotations Swink for was the first week of spring to support tower
8 Java 5 and Java 8.
The major reasons for our right are Java 5 brought in an additional support in Java 8 brought in things
like functional programming and other stuff.
So those are two important releases of Jawa and splintery was the first one to support our five.
First one to use jabber 5 in its implementation and spring Well the first one to support Java 8 features
we had to wait until the fight before Jawa 8 features were used in this spring framework itself because
it had to still support C6.
So if springform book what was using Java 8 features tend to not be able to support Java 6 or 7 and
other stuff.
So spring itself was not really using the Java 8 features but applications which were built in spring
could have used the Java 8 feature so without being 4:0 you could build up applications which used Java.
A major change in Springfield was the support for aircraft controller.
This was the time when their services started picking up very well and started moving towards address
full services.
And now we are moving to a micro 76.
So for was the first one to introduce the address controller to support the implementation of full so
users and also support for geocache the Java API for caching was introduced as part of 4.1.
Fight is the first question of spring.
Well there is a functional framework so you can use the concepts of functional programming to even develop
your application control.
One of the important things that I was working on is this thing called tweaks.
It's related to Java modularity the size of the Java installation has went up almost ten times since
July 1 to Java 8.
So if I have to install a JVM for Java 8 I would need more than 150 B and that's a lot of memory when
it comes to your DD races and for jobs to support such kind of devices.
We should be able to live with much less memory today.
The way Java is is if I want to double up any job application I would need the that JVM to be present.
I cannot say I want this part of JVM only and that's what jawab modularity with GSA aims to bring in
and spring five aims to support the DXO approach to Java modularity Screen-Free also has good support
for re-active programming in re-active programming.
A lot of emphasis is on building applications around event so when something happens we generate that
event and the rest of the application reacts to that spring five through spring.
Flex brings in support for the active programming Catrine is one of the evolving languages.
As far as the JVM languages are concerned and what Goatley you can write job applications in much less
a number of lines and typing fight has good support for Scotland and it's what you would discuss at
high level.
What is different important features in different versions of spring.
And what would the features in being five and then the next really Obery.