And putting there are a wide range of models such as in the spring Facebook when we talk about job applications
we build applications with multiple years each layer has its own concern that it's trying to implement.
Right.
You have a leader whose concern is to get the data from the browser or get the look.
If it's a web service then provide the external interface so that it does all the translations from
you were just one format to your beans are from your similar format to your beans or things like that.
So that's kind of the roll off of their framework to provide the viewer to provide the external interface
the business layer is concerned with the logic.
So it's concerned with what is the business logic of the application.
How do I make sure that the business logic is written well how do I make sure that transactions are
properly implemented and things like that.
Those are the concerns of a business leader.
The data layer is concerned with how do we talk to a database how they talk to an external system.
How do we talk to a big data or data stored.
Each of these layers have different concerns and Spring Framework has different models for each of these
early years.
And also there are things called cross-cutting concerns which are concept of multiple layers and spring
also has models to support that.
Let's start with the core container the core container is the crux of this.
Putting in the core features of spring as we discussed earlier our dependency injection or door wiring
managing the beans.
So this is where all those features beyond core and context context here actually means application
context and also has to be used at Spring expression language to support the definition of beans and
things like that.
So this is the core container.
This is where all you are.
In fact we all your application can text and all that features come in.
Next we will talk about the date earlier early spring has its own JTB framework called Spring JEDEC
spring JD B.C. makes it easy to talk to a relational database with typical JEDEC.
When you talk to a database you need to do a hundred different things and with daily b c you don't need
to do any of those.
We'll look at the BBC in detail a little later.
So if you have JEDEC application if it's let's say taking thousand lines you'd see that with spin day
TVC you can do the same thing in less than 200 250 lines.
Spring has good integration with the autumn frameworks object relational mapping frameworks being commits
well with Hibernate which is one of the popular autem implementations.
Spring also has good same model object SML mapping modules so it has good integration with other object
ex-MIL mapping frameworks.
For example Jack SSB-B and spring also has good integration with James spring.
JMS provides JMS implementation you'd be able to talk to other applications or the QS using JMS using
springiness.
Spring has built in support for transactions as well.
You'd be able to use Spring transactions and manage transactions for your JPA application.
Are you a hibernated based application or DJT BCBS based application.
Any of them moving onto the web here.
Spring has really good support for serviette and Bartlett.
And spring has a very ambitious frameup of its own.
It's called Spring and VC using spring and.
You can develop web applications very easily and also being has good support for rest.
So the spring MVC framework and all that used to Dola rest full applications spring also has a model
to support Reg socket programming.
So we looked a day earlier.
We looked at baby and there are things Veach I related to multipage that these are called cross-cutting
concerns typically cross-cutting concerns are things like logging exception handling and things like
that.
These are concerns of all the layers which are present in your application.
For example security as well AOP is a very good way to implement your cross-cutting concerns aspect
oriented programming.
Spring provides a basic aspect oriented programming model of its own and also has good support for AOP
frameworks like aspect.
We look at these two aspects a little later aswell.
Last but not the least important of the Mondial is spring d'Este.
One of the most important reasons why Spring is very popular is the dependency injection and with dependency
injection you'd be able to write tests very easily.
We'll be able to write uniters integration tests very easily.
It's spring and spring test helps you to write unit tests and integration Yes in this we do.
We took a quick look at all the spring models.
The most important thing is the fact that all the spring modules share the same version as the spring
framework.
So when I say there is a new release of spring spring 5 then it means there would be a new release for
all these modules with the version 5.
That's the most important difference between models and projects.
When I talk about models they'll have the same release version as the base spring frameworks in the
mix.
Media will look at spring projects.
These are things which are related to spring but they don't share the same version so probably when
I say spring version 5 and springboard might be using a version to see so they will have different work
shouldn't compare to spring and spring modules.
We'll look at that in detail in the next week.
Until then my.