The last step will look different.
Bring more dudes on the spring.
Models have the same release version as the Spring Framework so they are almost like they are part of
the Spring Framework.
There are other things spring does other than the Spring Framework and it's modules these are called
spring projects these spring projects provide solutions for different problems faced by enterprise applications
in this review.
Let's look at a few of them.
Let's start with spring.
What is one of the most popular books were developed micro services today.
Within a few years spring boot has become the most popular framework used for developing Microsoft releases.
Spring what makes it very very easy to develop applications quickly with just like start up projects
auto configuration actuator Springwood makes galloping applications especially Microsoft resus of coke.
The other important spring spring project is doing cloud.
We know that the world is moving towards the cloud right.
Everybody wants to deploy their applications in the cloud and therefore it's not sufficient if we don't
have good applications.
We have to develop our native applications.
We would want to be able to dynamically configured applications we would be able to dynamically connect
them.
We would be able we would want to be able to dynamically deploy applications cloud they do applications
need a lot of different features.
So if you have a Microsoft Office which is D'Erlach be using spring boot you can use cloud to cloud
enable my groceries bring data provide a consistent data access.
If I go a few years back there was only one kind of databases that we typically connect to.
We were going to do a proper school database.
Today there are bendin of North equal databases.
We have a mix of data sources so we have noise.
I mean we have a wide variety of noise levels.
We have high school databases as well.
How do you ensure that the way I'm accessing data from all this stuff is remaining consistent that what
this data aims to solve to bring integration on the other hand addresses problems with application integration.
There is something called enterprise application integration patents.
It's a very famous book.
Spring integration implements the patents which are recommended in the spring integration helps us in
connecting enterprise applications ready very easily.
Not all processing is done online.
Some of the processing is also done in batch applications batch applications have their own requirements
like for example I would want to be able to restart a bad job from where it failed or I would want to
be able to track down exactly what's happening in a batch in much much more of my new detail.
Spring Bache provide those kinds of features it enables developing batch applications very easily.
Security is one of the important part of galloping applications.
You'd want your applications to be secure whether you are developing a web application whether you're
looking at rest service or anything that you Delap you'd want to protect it.
So Spinx security provide solutions for securing your applications whether it's a web application or
whether it's the rest that is Spring has support for multiple security being Security has support for
multiple security options like basic authentication or thought integration or what do for example being
hate with enables you to develop hato is compatable services interest.
It's not sufficient if you just returned it.
You'd also want to return the related links that would help the consumer to understand where to go from
here saying hey do it would help you to do that very easily.
What we are looking at are sound of the spring projects they're just touching the tip of the iceberg.
There are a lot of those spring projects like spring webservices spring fashion spring social spring
mobile and spring.
Android which are solving problems in various different places has not really restricted itself to just
disappearing from work and got involved in a lot of wide variety of projects.
All this stuff you are learning as part of this printing course would also be useful when you are developing
on any of these spring projects.
And then the next step Boing.