Come to this we do we would be talking about a couple of questions.
Let's start with the first question.
What is the simplest way of ensuring that we are using singular mission of all spring related dependencies.
The problems you would have typically in your application is you don't want to specify.
This seems to bring question multiple times right.
If you have sprinklered Spring been spring AOP and different modules from spring you're making use of
you want to make the same version you want to use the same version of spring for all of the spring modules.
The easiest way of ensuring to do that is by using something called a bill of materials the paint seat.
So this bill of materials being dependency declaims the dependency versions for all these putting modules.
Once you put this in in your dependency management.
So there's a section called dependency management or into dependency management section.
If we add a dependency on the spring frame we're born for five point zero point zero Ridleys for example.
Then in your dependencies you don't need to specify diversion at all.
Diversion for the spin context will be picked up from the spring frame but so here the release version
ofspring from Obama's 5 0 0 release.
So the version of spin context which will be used will also be 5 0 0 Togolese and same is the case for
all those dependencies as well.
For example you talking about Springhaven web which is the dependency to your web applications it's
spring NBC or if you're talking about spring or green beans you don't need to specify the version from
now on.
So a lot you need to do is include dependency management indeed include the bomb in the dependency management
and that's it.
You don't need to specify a question for any of your sping dependencies and so forth.
The next question would be talking about is what some of the design patents which I used in Spring Framework
there are quite a few design patterns which I use in putting framework right.
When we talk about being MVC which we'll be talking about later you'd see that there is something called
Dispatches so late any request from the browser would first go to the dispatcher server left and only
then will it go to any of the other controllers.
This pattern is called for and control that.
And so all the quotes from the browser would first go to the dispatcher servlet DISPATCHER So that would
identify the right controller and distribute the thing to the controllers.
So that's one good example the front controller pattern dispatcher service.
The other important thing which brings us is managing the beans and the dependency injection.
So these are two other patents which spring uses.
So when we develop a spring application we are using a prototype so we are creating one instance of
the bean that's the prototype pattern and also we are using the dependency injection pattern because
all that we would be doing is doing component and at our door Wired The Bean Factory and the application
contex implementation of the factory patents because those are the factories which manage the beans.
One of the other design pattern which is frequently used in spring is Template Method.
If you look at abstract controller or if you look at JVC template or dimiss template all these are examples
of Template Method patterns.
If you look at the abstract controller it's an abstract class.
It defines an abstract method called handle request internal and what it does is it defines all the
logic around the handling requests internal in this handle request method to kind of create a put around
the handle requests internal.
I can go ahead.
All right.
They handle requests internal and implement a version of it myself.
But the basic wrap around it is provided by abstract control.
This is basically what is called a template method.
But then the next question we would want to talk about is what are some of the important swing and additions
you have used.
Actually during the last year with us we discussed about quite a few in addition so you can actually
quote any of them to at complainant's at depositary control at a wired primary qualifier and configuration
and configuration if you remember it was used to define a spring on its configuration.
So if we want to define the configuration for us being convicted of spying application context to be
used at configuration we can define beans in there in this video.
We took a quick look at some of the basic questions related to spring.
How do we ensure that one version of being dependencies bomb some of the design patterns used in speaking
framework we talked about prototype factory dependency injection and controller and template method.
And we look at this important being and additions under Linux we do boy.