Before we end this section on spring we would want to discuss a high level question about putting framework
in this tweet.
Typically ask questions like What do you think about putting Priem book why it's being popular or can
you give a big picture overview of the spring frame.
How do you go about answering that.
That's basically what we will discuss in this medium.
When we talk about spring in Book I would really look at it from three different perspectives right
architecture design and your programming or coding.
And other than that we can also talk about the different features ofspring framework different sping
models which are present and also about the different spring projects which are present.
These are all important things that we would need to cower when we are asking any questions related
to any of this stuff you are seeing on the screen right now you can choose any of those things which
you are really comfortable with.
For example when I talk about architecture one of the important things that beings have put is very
very flexible architectures.
Earlier we looked at multiple layers in a web application.
Right.
So the lab layer that earlier as well as your business lead.
Let's dig deep web layer for example.
Spring has good support for scraps as well as spring has its own NBC frameup the fact that I'm using
spring does not restrict the choice I have with the Web at NBC so I can still use traps or I can use
sping NBC or I can use any other thing.
For example if I want to use JCP for views sping has good support for it if they want.
Because free market for use even then Bing has good support for it.
For example if I want to use Aspect Oriented Programming then springs supports basic aspirator into
programming by itself.
But it also has good integration with Aspect Oriented Programming framework like aspected.
So that's very important when we're talking about something from an architectural perspective.
I want to have the flexibility using the Spring Framework should not reduce the amount of choices I
have to develop my application.
That's one of the most important features of Spring Framework.
It does not really restrict any of your choices when I am making use of the spinning framework next
from the perspective design.
We already talked about by coupling loose coupling house being promoted.
Applications do have good loosely coupled design.
So because of the loosley couple design you would see that code would be very easy to use.
So whenever I would want to write a unit test because we have designed the application in a loosely
coupled with with all the dependencies demarcated really well you'd see that when I develop an application
mid-spring it's very easy to unit test it.
What are we talking about popularity of spring Primack.
I think these are the most important reasons.
I mean very very flexible in terms of the architecture helps in designing loosley couple applications
which can be easily unit tested different features offspring which enable these features are dependency
injection I use the containers we all already dogbone out our wiring and components.
And the other thing you can talk about when such questions are asked.
Talk about being modeled.
What are the different models you have with things like that and also talk about the different spring
projects that you have with in this video.
We took a quick look at how to answer questions related to Big picture with respect to spring frame
but things like what do you think about it or why is it popular.
Can you give a big picture of this playing framework and things like that until the next video.