You come to this course from in 20 minutes I can tell you that in 2018 it has 90000 blistered and six
doesn't find it place five star reviews on our courses and all 10 hours of content in this course.
But these numbers do not make a difference to you and your learning unless you make the best use of
discourse.
We recommend you to set one goal for yourself and commit at least 28 minutes a day to learn something
new.
I am of course kidding.
I'm a great believer that if you learn something new for at least half an hour every day you'd reach
the top five percent of any career that you would choose.
And 28 minutes was disclosed this domain name I got.
Now the story you set yourself a goal and the reward.
Now I will tell you why this call should be what you should be doing for that Haffner you have committed
65 percent of the new Java projects use spring and spring.
Good.
A big chunk of that is Flippy's web services and micro services are being built with spring and our
spring springboard.
Three hundred percent is the increase in number of micro services that are being built with springboard
in the last two years.
Seventy percent is the percentage of real world projects using Mavin to manage dependencies and get
as Washington control.
I would recommend forking the repository of the course and I recommend you like it do to make me happier
in the world of my growth.
This is where we create a number of small micro services and that's what we do in this course do we
create a number of small projects to ensure you have the skills to set up a new project from ground
up.
Now in this video with a couple of recommendations.
A big chunk of the audience for this cause is starting to put in the initial part of the course.
We repeat a few important concepts.
If you are an experienced programmer have some patience for the first hour or so and we should be good
to go.
The important thing we would want you to know is that you retain 90 percent of the concepts.
If you watch the videos.
Do these steps along with me and repeat it again.
If you made it here its time to open up your calendar and reserve at least half an hour to learn every
day.
Good luck and I'll see you in the next week you.