Welcome to this video we will introduce you to.
I did have both agree get have depositary for this course.
It's good to have dot com slash in 2010 that last spring.
Hi Friend interview hi and guide.
So it did not spring high for an interview HIF and guide described depositary contains the presentation
which you'd be using in this course as well as five different projects.
Also present here is the list of 200 questions that we'll be talking about in this course.
At the bottom of the good habit depositary is a section called Getting Started.
If you want to understand more about Mavin G-Unit Marketo you can use DVD-R's which are present in here
also present.
Here is a section on installing the tools you can follow this playlist to install the different tools
that we would need as part of this code.
This would help you to install Eclipse and use embedded maven as part of Eclipse.
There's also a PDA guide to help you in here.
We know there are instructions that would help you to set up and run the code examples which we have
in the project.
I'll see you in the next review.
We will set up the presentation until then.