It this way you will help you set up the presentation that we would be using in the course the presentation
which we are going to use is in our get her repository in 28 minutes.
Springing up you gay.
So if you are down there what you can do is you can click on or download if you are familiar with it
then you can do a clone.
If you're not then probably downloading does it is the best option for you.
So you can download the zip and zip zip file to of all the click download it will download a zip file
downloads folder and unzip it to some folder on your local hard drive and zip zip file to this folder
so it's been in your guide master.
And if you go to the presentation you'd be able to see a file called spring in question started.
See what you can do is you can drag it and put it in your favorite browser.
So let's drag it and put it in my browser and do so.
Launch up the presentation what you can do here is just press F..
This would start the presentation in full screen.
All you have to do is press F and you can see all these slides of this presentation.
The first few flights are the introduction to the course.
After that all the questions the code snippets which would be using and the presentation instructions
everything would be present inside the presentation.
And if you'd want to move out just skip it would take you out of the full screen mode so as to enter
the fullscreen mode escape to get out of it.
And if you press escape again it would show kind of the index as Skip Skip.
It would show the index so that you can easily navigate through these slides.
Have you set the entire presentation up.
You can also navigate by typing the slide numbered in the browser so no Amant slide number 200 or if
I would want to go to 300.
I can go there so you can see that there are quite a lot of flights which are present in here.
In total we have about three hundred thirty one light which would be going through during this code.
I'll see you in the next you.