This with you let's get a quick overview of the order in which we would be approaching different things
in this court.
One of the important things is you can keep around like you would want even though we go in a specific
order we would start with spring spring NBC and then go to Spring Springwood and so on and so forth.
You can actually directly skip to spring but if that's the topic you are really interested in the order
in which we will be covering topics in the discourse.
Our roots start with spring.
Because about the basics of spring like loose coupling dependency question of control application context
actual application context job application context and different.
In addition to which I used in spring we talk about the default school.
We talk about different types of injections set an injection and construct injection.
And we would talk about how to debug problems with springform book.
We would talk about primary at qualifier annotations.
You talk about the new features into pling framework.
What are the different spring model to represent what are the different spin projects which represent
and we would end D.S. giving you a big picture of the Spring Framework.
Understanding why is it popular.
In the next section we would move into spring and we see what we would be talking about is the basics
of our pictures of web applications model one model to model different controller and things like that.
After that we would talk about the basics of spring and we see a simple flow in spring NBC we talked
about Dispatches several that you resolve with a moral model and view and how you map requests.
We also talk about validation and form backing objects.
We use Binding result to do our validations and we'll all to talk a little bit about being formed X
and model in-session and after that we move into a section on springboard.
We try to understand the different goals and features in spring but we're trying to compare spring with
spring and spring and we see we talk about other projects or configuration spring initialiser we talk
about profiles and also about actuator and we'll end this section by talking about command line.
Run them in the next section we would go into database connectivity.
We talk about these things we see and g.p we talk about entity manager persistence context the different
types of relationships in Jaypee and all.
How do you configure GPA.
One of the important things is this kind of an all of U.S. I mean that it needs a really detailed cost
to go into the details of everything related to GAAP.
So this kind of giving you an all world view of Gippi while still staying in touch with how you would
use spring to connect to GP in the next section we would be talking about sping data.
What is the need for spring that what is being AJP And what are the different kinds of repositories
that are unpleasant.
That we would move into unit testing.
We would look at three example unit tests.
One is using Machi my favorite mocking work as well as the default mocking cream book with spring but
we would also look at how to write a unit test with Mark NBC and also how to write integration test
with spring boot.
After that we would move into AOP understand the different concepts which are related to ERP like aspect
bind code and different things like that.
We'll also understand the most popular AOP from book Aspasia and compare it with the spring will.
After that we moved into a section on topup services.
We would talk about the contract first approach of developing web services with spinning Web services.
We talk about the different content related to superb services so so peda so bored the soap envelope
and things like that along the W-S DL Xs D Jax be in point and we also talk about message dispatches
that we end with the section on press for that.
So he says the world is moving to its macro so he says and this will web services play a key part in
that.
We'll talk about what is best what are the key concepts in designing.
Let's Philippe and also the best practices related to them.
We look at creating gate and portmanteaux what on the sort and also what are the different response
state to Sissi should respond back for those requests that we look at had Dior's have to document a
restful Web services using swagger.
We understand what is in negotiation and also understand how to add similar support for your restfully
Web services.
Along with discussing about the best practices related to exception handling and worshipping that really
a wide range of topics that we would try and cover during this court.
So you can feel free to skip around to the section that you would want to do first and then feel free
to skip around to other sections as well in the next week.
We would start with discussing about the basics of spring.
Well until then.