Welcome back in this section we would start discussing about the questions related to spring but.
We'll start with these questions in this review.
What is being.
What are the important goals of really good and what are the important features of spring.
Typically when we look at Spring applications as being MBC applications they have a lot of configuration
that is needed right.
For example let's talk about being in VC.
You need to configure a dispatcher servlet you need to configure a component Can you need to configure
Buras all were if we would want to use static libraries like bootstrap then we would need to configure
Bebb job so that we can deal with the static content.
And also when we configure security there are a lot of things that we would need to configure.
So typically this kind of configuration it might be done in Java code using configuration or this can
be done in an application context example.
So either way there's a lot of conflagration that you would need to do before you can get started with
your application.
In addition to this probably you would want to configure error controller to handle exceptions that
happens and things like that.
So there are a lot of configuration that you would need.
The other factor is also the fact that we are moving a Microsoft.
Is this all the architectures are moving to make those services and we do not have a lot of time to
set up a lot of micro services right.
If instead of one big application I have 20 smaller micro services then I don't have a lot of time to
set up each one of them.
I would want to be able to quickly get up and running with the application.
I would want to start running the application and focusing on the business logic I shouldn't need to
focus on all the technical stuff of how to configure things and things like that.
What are the goals of Spingold the goals of the most important goal of scoring goals is to provide a
QuickStart to spring projects.
If I want to create a new spinning music project I should be able to start doing start developing it
within half an hour.
Or if I want to set up J-P to connect to a database I should be able to set it up in another half hour.
The most important goal of spring.
How does being good achieves that is by being opiniated so it makes a lot of exemptions about how things
have to be done.
It takes an opinion and price to implement it.
But the most important thing is you can actually override the opinion so springboard provides options
where you can actually change what is configured by default.
The other goals of springboard are related to non functional features so it aims to provide a lot of
functional features like monitoring error handling and things like that.
The last goal of spring boot is no.
Generation Zero code generation as I call it.
So there is no coordination at all.
As far as being Booby's concern what are the important features of being.
Or have the most important features of springboard is something called auto configuration.
We look at auto configuration.
Indeed did in a later we do.
In a nutshell it's basically when you add a specific jar into the class.
But let's say I'm adding a stinging message into the classpath.
Springboard can look at it and recognize the fact that spring is in the class but it would automatically
configure all the things that are needed to do that application.
So you could configure a dispatcher servlet resolver.
It would also can configure a message converter and all the things that are needed to doubtable web
application are configured automatically.
And this feature is called auto configuration.
If you add in a web application that spring Bebb jar then you get the configuration related to web application.
If you add in a J-P let's say a hibernate just in.
Then you'll get the configuration that is related to connecting to the database so it would create a
data source.
It would create an entity manager or factory and all the other stuff that you would need to be able
to connect to a database with ease.
You see the other important feature of spring boot is something called Spring boot start a project to
look at data projects in detail a little later.
Or start a project provide a QuickStart to different types of applications whether you would want to
open up a web application AJP application of episodes application or whatever other applications you'd
want to dial up.
Spring would start a project provide you a quick start to it.
Springboro actuator helps you in monitoring your application.
It exposes a lot of details about the application so that monitoring it becomes really easy.
The last feature about building boot is embedded Sellwood.
So with Springle applications you can embed the server inside the appliable job.
So things like Tomcat JT they can be included in your jar file.
And when you actually run the application on the server you don't need Tom-Kat installed separately
because despite of your application will discuss about this concept of embedded in detail a little later
respin in this video we took a quick look at what is being Goodwater its important goals and what are
the important features really cause about all these features in detail in the next few years.
Until then.