Before we get much further into spring boot you'd want to understand how it compares to spring.
Spring is actually spring spring spring and we have clear well separated responsibilities and each of
them are independent to us.
So with application we would use Spring spring NBC and spring but all of them together and we would
use spring board to configure spring and spring and see if that's confusing.
Let's make that clear in this video.
Let's talk about spring.
What is spring.
Spring as we talked earlier the most important feature is dependency injection.
Right so all that is at the core of everything related to spring is this concept of dependency injection
and you'll see in mission control application context.
In fact that these are really the fundamental concepts in spring.
So what does being aimed to do if you have a class like this.
Well this is tight coupling because this is of tightly coupled to this welcome service.
I cannot have that.
So what I would do is I would actually have to ride on there and thereby would be able to unit test
the specific controller much more easily.
So mid-spring would be able to introduce dependency injection and would be able to do unit testing very
easily as well.
The first thing that being helps us do is to write loosley couple accord.
The other problem that's being solved is the duplication of code.
So if you look at being JVC it reduces the amount of code that you would need to write by almost certain
papers and because it reduces all the noise that the exception an exception handling code and also all
the code to set the parameters in all the code to dig details out of the results.
All of that it removes and it only leaves the crux of the business logic in there.
Eliminate all the plumbing code and duplication code and also the problems being solved is good integration
with other frameworks so if I want to use cloud to know my web application or if I want to connect to
hibernate in my web application spring provide very easy integration with all of them if I want to connect
to James or if I want to do transaction management has really good support to all that kind of stuff.
Basic problems being solved is dependency injection by bringing in loose coupling and also make the
application testable.
It tries to remove the problem of duplication and plumbing code and it has really good integration with
other frameworks.
Now what does being SBC do to bring him in.
He actually provides a great way of helping you were web applications.
So it provides a decoupled way but simple concepts like dispatcher so late model and users.
It makes it very easy to develop web applications.
All there's a clear separation of concerns with spring NBC makes it very easy to develop their applications
and also it helps us let's say if I want to switch from JCP to some other thing for a view it's being
MVC it's a very easy thing to do.
Now where the spring would fit in spring boot or let it tries to do is all the configuration that is
needed based bring into being NBC it will try to eliminate that.
It will be limited by this feature called auto configuration.
So what does it do say is there is no need to configure a dispatcher said with an auto configured for
you there is no need to configure data are not allowed to configure it for you.
There is no need to configure entity manager or factory or transaction manager as well to configure
it for you and it will also define a default component can as well.
Thereby it makes it very very simple to drill up spring and spring and easy applications spring boot
aims to make it very easy to develop spring and spring and VC applications.
How does being good do that things in this way.
So when somebody adds in a spring and besieger can bring some intelligence into it.
When somebody add a hibernate What can I do something more automatically.
So what does it look said defraying books which had available at declasse but so it looks at different
books in the class but and also existing configuration which is provided as part of the spring context.
And based on this springboard provide something called auto configuration.
In this video we looked at what is the role of spring.
What is the role of sping NBC and what is the role of spring board until the next video.