This would you we would talk about something called at springboard application.
So if you look at any springboard application this is the annotation which will be present everywhere
right on top of any good application class.
At the root is this thing called springboard application and we use this application to launch up the
entire application.
Here we are seeing spring application that ran this class and we are able to do that because this is
a spring board Application class.
So what are the features that Pingu application brings in.
That's basically what we would look at.
So if we look at being good application there are three important things that it does.
Number one it has springboard configuration.
Second it is enabling auto configuration.
Third it does a component can Springboro configuration tells that this is a configuration for springboard
application.
This is very similar to the ED configuration annotation that we use in us putting context right in spring
applications we use at configuration.
So Spingold configuration is just an enhancement of that.
So this tells this good application is going to create a spring context.
That's basically what it tells us.
The second thing which it does is they enable auto configuration.
So what happens with Springboard is you would want to configure based on whatever frameworks at present
in the class.
But this feature called auto configuration needs to be turned on.
So who is doing that.
That's done by the spring board application.
In addition it says that enable our configuration to auto configuration is turned on.
The last thing it does is also component can this being what the application is in this bag.
Cage so it automatically turns on a component scan on this basically bad case.
So what.
There were things that you have in this package directly into all the files which are under this package
so this rest for web applications in the package that's full of services that they package it in.
So everything in this package will be scanned for components and all this stuff would be big deal.
So I don't need to explicitly define a component.
I'm basically a Springwood application creates the best framework for spring Buddh.
So it says there's a spin configuration it enables auto configuration and it enables a component.
And until the next week you were way.