Welcome come back in this with.
Let's look at auto configuration and also how can you find more information about the configuration.
We have been talking about our contribution a lot since we started with spring board and we'll be talking
a lot about it because this is the most fundamental feature of spring.
Right so it's being bought looks at frameworks which are available on the classpath and all the existing
configuration of application based on which would provide the configuration that is needed.
Develop an application with the supreme books.
This is basically what is our configuration.
So springboard autoconfig good stuff based on what I wear glasses are available in the class but that's
basically what we're job at available in your dependencies.
It took at the start up log.
If you look at the start up blog you would see something called Dispatches 7 that it's mapped to slash
it's mapping slash error on to a space which thinks it's mapping this last object and something of that
kind in there as well.
So all this is a result of the auto configuration been Boots's.
There is a class called Dispatches overlaid on the class but so it configures a dispatcher servlet it
sees that I'm trying to develop a web application and then it can be good error handling thing as well
for.
So this is demand for English and we have been talking about it a lot.
How does all the configuration work.
So where is a configuration implemented.
The Octagon provision is implemented in a jar called springboard auto configured or job.
If you look at your dependencies there is something called boot or to configure Baer's underlings.
You're using Dunja and all.
Here is the configuration for all the different things that spring board works with.
So you can see a lot of packages which are present in here.
Look at the configuration related to AB.
If you look at the web package there are a lot of auto configuration which is presented for web as well.
So you see a controller and you'll see error MVC or auto configuration.
You see the HDP message connectors for just on auto configure.
You can see Jackson HTP message converters are configured as well.
These they use to translate or can what you were just on to beans and beans to Geass on as well as you'd
see dispatches servlet auto configuration similar to this.
There are a lot of packages where the configuration for all the other stuff is defined as well.
So you can plug and play around with this being able to configure out and try and figure out what's
happening in there to understand what about auto configuration when springboard launches up to look
at all the auto configuration things which are present in here and fires which of them are matching
the conditions.
So you can see this is conditional on class this being available.
So if this class is available this article configuration will be fired.
So it is conditional on missing bin.
So if this bean is not there then configure this in these all these gases within the conditions when
each of these configurations are really good.
If you want to understand our country curation in depth one of the things you can do is good application
that properties and turn on debug logging all here.
I've turned on the blogging for my application for the Spring Framework.
If you don't need on then you would see something called an auto configuration report that is printed.
So you can see all the information that we're seeing right now is because of the auto configuration
we pulled to the auto configuration report shows.
What are the positive matches which of which are all the other configurations which were configured.
And also it shows what the other things that were not matched as well it shows that negative matches.
These are the things which do not match.
These are not matching because of a specific condition it shows the details of all that as well.
The other way you can look up auto configuration information is by going to the spring board actuator.
So if you go to the entry point of spring boot actuator localhost ADHD application will look we talk
about being good at it a little later as well.
The thing which we wanted to focus on is the auto configuration which is present in here so if you go
to auto one figuration you'll be able to see all the details of what these autoconfig that you'll be
able to see that the specific Beanie's are configured and why.
So you have to do that just as well as you have something called negative images.
Search for the matches.
You have both these details present in here.
In this way we try to get a big picture of photo configuration or the last few video as we understood
what our configuration is and indeed we do.
We focused on finding more information about auto configuration we talked about the fact that to find
more about our configuration I can go to the jobs being built configured or jet and all don't debug
logging on or Also I can use being.
She waited until the next studio.