Welcome back in this video we would talk about it.
Why is that so important.
What is it.
But it's well it's good.
And what the other.
And what it said was that I supported race being.
So why does the concept of that so were very important.
Think about this.
Now we are moving towards the world of Mike services and we are developing a lot of small applications.
So to deploy this more applications on the server we would want to have as less prerequisite as possible.
So if I have a server let's say a unique set of which was already installed.
If I have a web application which needs Tom-Kat then first thing I need to do is to install tomcat on
the so I'd I would need to install Java.
Then I need to install tomcat and then I would then be able to install IMAP location.
But even before installing the application I need to reconfigure the server with all the stuff that
I would need to do.
So is a lot of steps that is involved in doing all this stuff in stuff that we can use embedded in the
concept of limited so what is basically that US so what is embedded as part of our application.
So the server is directly part of your job.
So the Tomcat for example is directly embedded into your job.
So if I want to run this application which is present in Java I don't need or Tomcat so because it gets
a what is inside our job.
All that I need to do is have Jalla on that machine too if I want to double up.
So if I want to deploy this application onto a deployment and we run into let's say I'm going to deploy
this application into Kubik and we are creating a cube box fresh all that they need to do is install
Jalla there.
That's the only thing I would need then I can go ahead and start running this job data down there because
they can't get what is already part of our job.
The concept of embedded server makes it easy to deploy our applications into the deployment in one big
cloud.
We would want to be able to easily create a new environment and remove Abbaye environment as in when
we need them.
Concept of embedded.
So what helps us do that pretty easily because we can take any system which has just job on it and deploy
that application and start running at the end of that so it removes the need to have so pre-installed
on the deployment and we don't mind the default embedded server for spinning boot IIS.
Don't get hurt.
It's been good also has support for D and underdo as the embedded.
So the thing is Spingold start up web is the startup which we would use typically to develop applications.
And this doctor has a data dependency on springboards started to get that Tomcat is the default dependency.
So if I want to switch trajectory or under to what I would need to do is first I would need to exclude
the static Tomcat.
So independence is a good start of web.
I'm excluding springboard Dr. Tom.
And then I'm adding in the dependency on JT so I'm adding in the JT style.
Similarly if I want to switch to underdo or that I need to do is instead of Jaydee I need to use and
go in here in this step we talked about embedded server.
Why is it important.
What is the default embedded server and what are the other ones which are supported by spring.
And then the next video we.