Welcome back.
We've been talking about the projects a lot until you know in this video.
Let's get a quick.
All of them.
And also we look at a few examples of startup projects.
So what are starter projects.
If you look at the spring board documentation this is the definition for a spring board start a project.
Doctors are convenient dependency descriptors so and when in dependency descriptor so it Bombarnac similar
things which define dependencies that you can include in your application with doctors you would get
a one stop shop for all spring and related technology that you would need.
Let's look at springboards start of web which is this data for developing web application.
If you look inside that specific jet all that you'll see is a simple on redig similar nothing else.
There's a single blue light which actually defines what all the different things that it provides.
But other than that all that which is present in there is a simple pondered Exham.
So what does this Parnevik similar contain.
If you look at this Bondra example it contains a dependency on this.
Does being good data which is kind of the default standard which is present in all these doctors.
Other than that it has a dependency on Giese on startup because spring Webb also supports restfully
Web services.
We would want to be able to convert someone to Java and Java to just one or two objects and object projects
on.
So this being good strategy will help you to do that.
You can see that there is a dependency on Tom-Kat.
That's how we would be able to get Tom get as the embedded server you can see that there is a dependency
on hibernate validator.
This is the default implementation of validation API.
And also there is a dependency on this spring MVC framework so you can see that this being booed starter
has all the dependencies that are needed to develop a typical web application.
So I don't need to worry about what question of each one of these do you or any of that kind of stuff
that I need to do is include this doctrine and everything else.
I would get for free.
If you look at this for data AJP this is for developing any hibernate applications are J-P applications
then you'd see a palm read simle also in here.
This Banyard example if you look at it it contains or does it contain.
It contains the basic starter again and you have status for AOP NJT B.C are also present in here and
then that we would have a dependency on hibernate code.
That's the default implementation of JPR.
As far as being good data is concerned you have the transaction API to be able to implement transactions.
And also we have spring data that included by default.
So these are the same books you would need to data up your JPA applications other then spring has aspects
as it says here it's just a convenient dependency descriptor.
So basically what we are doing there is defining Palm is similar to with all the dependencies that we
would need to set up that kind of application if it's a web application what would you need to develop
a web application.
All those are present in your dependency descriptors now that we understand what's in a startup project.
Let's look at what all the different starters which are bailable.
The first doctor is a good start of Web services.
So one important thing you need to remember is even though it's called Web services it's only used to
dial the top web services for restfully Web services.
We have to use splaying would start over there.
When we say it's been good to start up Web services we're talking about soap Web services so things
like defining your access these generating D-W SDL from that defining good end point handling your soap
requests all that can be done using spring boot start over.
So this thing would start a Web is the one to develop web applications and also address all that.
So is this springboard start a test is also included by default in almost all the projects.
So when you create a project with springboard you would by default include sping would start this because
you have to write you need this.
You can also write integration tests using sping good stuff.
Just saying good strategy ODBC will help you to write traditional GBC based applications so here we
are talking about getting C and NJT we applications so you can write a query and get the details out
of the database and things like that.
Spring would start to hate us is when we develop a regular web application.
We also want to add features to it.
We'll discuss about eight years later when we talk about full applications in detail.
It's been good.
Straight ahead to us helps us to add hideous features to your application or actually do you address.
So this spring would start the security helps you you add authentication to your web and there's food
there services spring would start the day.
Is the start for developing G.P.A. with hibernated.
And if you want to implement gashing in your application then you can use springboards dyadic gash.
The great thing is sping would start at cash not only support the default gashing with things like E.H.
cash and stuff like that it also get support distributed caching with things like his guest the last
part that we will talk about the spring would start at the dentist.
So whenever you have a J-P entity which you would want to expose to the outside world using it as web
services you can easily do that using a springboard data did it just it helps you to take your spring
data repositories and make them available as a restful web series.
In this video we looked at startups and we looked at the examples of that and didn't actually do but
we.