Welcome back.
And this video we'll will talk about something called Start a period.
We look at what are the different things which are pleasant and start appearing and also really understand
how being good and for this common dependency management for all that study projects.
Let's get started now.
If you look at a spring springboard application application which is Darel abusing sping what you would
see sping would start appearing present in there.
So it's the parent form which is used in almost all springboard applications.
If you look at springboards start a parent you'd see that it has a parent on its own.
It's called splitting dependencies and it defines a lot of different things the different things that
D-Star appeared in defense.
We already looked into what dependencies being present at the top.
You can also see that it defined the D for Joe Walsh.
It defines the encoding of the project and also defines the source and target for the completion.
But the most important part for us being would start appearing is this dependencies parent because the
springboards dependency parent is where all the versions of dependencies define.
So when you're using sping boot you don't need to define the version of any of the dependencies because
all the versions I defined in displaying both dependencies.
So if I'm using E.H. Gesh 3 then the version is defined in here if I'm GFC This is the question if I'm
using Tomcat This is the question.
One of the problems I used to frequently face before I use Springwood was what question off the dependencies
would play together very well.
So if I'm using a specific question or spring then what version of hibernate validator should I use.
What version of Jackson should I use.
What version of JFC should I use.
What question of sibling security should I use.
That's always a confusing thing because you don't know when there would be conflicts.
So you have to do some kind of a trial and error and figure out what are the compatable versions of
different free works.
That's what springboard eliminate.
By use by specifying all the dependency worshipped in springboard dependencies it says OK you as a programmer
you don't worry about the wash ins you just say what you need.
I know what all the compatable motions so inspiring would be dependencies all the wash for more than
250 jobs are defined and all the portioning is taken care in there.
So I don't need to worry about which wash to use all that I need to tell Springboro is I want to use
Jackson that's it I don't need it diversion to use.
I need it.
I want to use security based on the washiness being I'm using it would automatically configure the right
spring security for me.
All that features sping would get through this thing called sping would start happening.
So what we look at in this particular video is the fact that shipping would start appearing depends
on spring boot dependencies.
I mean it's been good that the parent has another Parent called Springwood dependences and Interlingua
dependences.
We manage the versions of almost all the dependencies that would be needed to develop springboard applications
and then this in this database and we define the Java wish that we would want to use.
Which question would you want to compile the Java code.
And then the next with you.