In this video will focus on something called spring in what being laser What can you use it for.
What kind of projects you can create using spring initialiser.
What is the fastest way to create projects with spring and spring.
Those are the things that map to just one answer.
Sping initialiser espying initialiser is basically a tool to create a spring projects spring into place
that is that dot dot dot dot you.
Once you go here you'll get to choose what is the dependency management tool you would need to use.
So what is the dependency management tool you would want to use.
I'm using Maiman.
You can say I want to create a job project the other languages which are supported are clean and groovy.
So I would want to create a job project.
And you can choose which version of springboard to use.
So you can choose any of the questions which are available in here and you'd be able to define what
the group idea and idea packed already up to your project.
The most important thing is you get to choose this style.
So we talked about a lot of different starters earlier or later verb or I would want to use JP I'd want
to connect to JMS.
I would want to add in sping security.
You can add a lot of dependencies like this.
If you don't know what dependencies are available in here you can actually switch to a full version
and just go further down and you would be able to see support for a lot of different things you can
add aspect oriented programming support you have web application support.
You have Jesse Jackson today will be a restful Web services with Jack's address.
You have support for yours.
You have a lot of different things related to sequel.
I mean which do in memory database JTB CJP and all that kind of stuff so you can add in all the dependencies
that you would need to want there is support for school as well.
And we also talked about streaming cloud so all the stuff related to spring cloud.
Also you can add in from here and last but not least is actuators.
You can also add actuator and the documentation for actuator as well.
So you can add in what are all the dependencies that you would need and you can click Genndy project.
This would generate a project for you with all these dependencies present in and you can just import
that project into eclipse and start working with it.
Bring initialiser is a place where you can create your spring projects very easily.
It would create a project based on your choice.
And you can import that project into your idea and very easily use it until the next video.
All right.