Well come back in this way.
Let's look at some of the important things related to application or probe by piece.
What is that position or properties What are some of the important things that can be customized in
application or properties.
Let's get started now.
So what is application that properties application properties is just something like a property file.
Right.
In spring if I open a application that properties I'd be able to configure a lot of different things
I can configure the lobby level up the application and I can configure either use which I would want
to make use of in the application as well.
Another example of the application that properties from one of our web services applications.
So if you look at it we are setting the be able to debug.
We are setting how to do this realization.
So you're saying don't see the latest date time stamps read Day Test Data not us not names stamps and
we are also disabling management security.
So if you look at actuator actuator we look at it in one of the subsequent steps by default.
When you add in actuator the securities enable.
So here we are just turning it off temporarily and other things that we can configure in is what should
be the username and password for security.
So if I'm turning basic security on here it's false but if you turn it on and you add it's being security
then you can set what should be the user id and password.
We are here we are setting it to use that name and password.
The other thing which we are configuring in here is we are setting choice to true.
So when any query is fired through GAAP then that Asgill will be printed to the log.
And also when we are using Jaypee and we are do as in memory database we can enable the hishe to control
what we are showing in here is some of the important things that can be configured through application
properties.
There are a huge range of things that you can configure to application properties.
A few other things which can be configured through application that properties include logging file.
So where should your logging file be present.
What should be the name and what should be part of it.
And also logging level we Lubet earlier so it can be debugged in four trees whichever level you would
want to set it to.
And also if you want to exclude certain auto configurations then you can configure that to application
properties.
You can configure the profiles that should be active through application not properties as well we'll
look at profiles a little later.
You can configure the error but by default they are about a slash error.
So if you want to change that you can configure that too by default as being good application launches
up on ADHD.
You can change that by configuring so weatherboard by default the HDP converter which is used for Jaison
is Jackson.
So if you want to use Jewson you can map that in here as well.
The thing is application that properties is the central place where you can configure a lot of things
related to springboard.
If you do a google search for springboard application properties you'd land up on an appendix.
This appendix contains all the common application properties that are present in spring boot you would
see that this is a huge file.
So if you were really interested to spend some time looking at all the properties which are present
in this file it will take a long time pleasing properties is basically used to configure your springboard
application so that you make use of all the configuration for all these doctors had to ramp application
properties.
And we looked at some of the important things which can be customized through application that properties
and in the next video play.