Well you come back in this we will look at something called externalised configuration.
We would want to add custom application properties to our application.
We learn how to do that using suppling wood and also we look at something called a configuration property
so these are all the questions that we would answer in this busy week.
We do.
So how do we actually the configuration using spleenwort in the earlier video.
We looked at application properties.
So properties is the fundamental way to extend lazed configuration.
And you can also use yammered syntax in application.
Yeah.
So you can use application properties or you can use application but YAML YAML stands for yet another
Markup Language O'Hehir instructing logging DOT level dot org that's being claimed book is called the
debug thing.
Logging level args being claimed.
But this is more readable format.
Even a human would be able to read this and understand this.
For example in the earlier one we said Abdur name is good at this and description is this but Indiamen
This is how it would look.
So app name description so almost like a hierarchical level you can use the Ammann are properties.
Either of these are good approaches to configure your application when you're developing your application
you'd want to have a few custom properties.
This is very important because some of the times your configuration might change from environment when
you meant for a specific feature you might want to enable it in their environment but disable it in
Kuwait or you might be trying out some features in your data which you'd want to turn off in production.
So in all these kind of situations externally configuration actionless configuration plays an important
and externalise configuration we are talking about in here is not really which is already made available
by spinning the things which we are talking about are ones which are custom So based on our feature
requirements how do we create our own configuration properties the way we can create configuration properties
in applications is by using at configuration properties.
Here I'm giving it a name basic.
So if I want to configure de-value for this I can do that is basic don't value basic message basic garden
number so I can configure it in application properties using that.
Now this is how you define your properties but how can you make use of these properties.
It's very simple game.
All you need to do is not a wide and basic configuration in.
So this is basic configuration that we have defined in here and just Arto wiring it in.
And I can make use of configuration not get message configuration or get number configuration.
That is when you know all the values from here can be made use of in our.
Here we are making use of it in a simple restful service but you can use it in any of the early years
whether it's a business leader or natally or audio over.
So this is how you define your properties this is how you make use of your properties that are configured
and this is how you configure your properties you are setting value is going to do messages going to
a number is called 200.
This is how you do it in application properties.
If you're using application or Yemen it's much more simple it's basic value through message and number.
So this enables us to be able to define custom application properties.
The most important advantage of the custom property route is the type safety.
So here I am trying to set a value of basic dog number to a value of ABC whereas if you look at our
configuration basic That number is a number.
So when I tried to set a string value to it there would be an exception application fail to start.
It this failed on what property value or type so and so which requires a type int.
I was not able to convert this ABC to.
That's basically what it's the good practice which we recommend for all applications which are based
on spring boot is the truth configuration properties to define all user application configuration.
You'll be making use of certain features from sping boots so those things you can anyway configure through
application properties but those properties to which you which are specific to your application which
are specific to your features that you are helping in your application.
Always use configuration properties to define them so you can have one being like this.
Hi.
Radke So here we have basic conversation probably you can have something like application configuration
indeed in which there is a hierarchy of beans which you can use to configure your application in this
video.
We looked at how Quixtar unlace configuration using springboard how well you can define custom application
properties using springboard.
And what is the use of configuration properties in the next when you will look at how to define different
values for each of these properties in different environments and building next video by.