Welcome back.
In this video we'll talk about profiles how you can define beyond for a specific profile and also how
you can create application configuration for a specific profile.
Typically when we develop applications we deployed them in different kinds of environments.
Right dev Kuei stage production your local environment as well so you have multiple environments in
which you applications can be deployed and the application configuration in each of these environments
will definitely be different.
So how do you handle those changes the way we would handle them is by something called a profile.
Springboard has this concept called profile built in profile is the way we can answer the question how
do you have different configuration for different environments.
The way we can have different configuration for different environment is by defining individual property
files for each one of them.
So all the common properties you can define in application are properties if you want to override any
of the properties in a basic neuron.
So let's say I want to override the properties in Dev and I can create application and properties in
Q8 application and create the properties.
So once I define this property the only thing I would Naden need to be doing is to set that profile
for that environment run into if in the queue when we don't mind I would want to make use of application
and Quader properties whatever it is defined in there.
Then I would need to set a profile of Q8 for that application.
How do I said this profile of you where I can set the profile of keyway by either when you're launching
up the job application Springwood application as a job application you can passing an argument saying
hey the spin that provides active is equal to you can say if it's cute or in application properties
application that properties file itself you can just print out profiles or the active cycle queue.
These are the two ways which are present where you can set a profile and based on the profile which
is present in their appropriate file from the application properties is pick up.
This allows us to configure different values in different environments or do you need to do is change
the profile.
So if I'm in production outside a profile of Prod. if I mean Q8 had the profile of Q8 as simple as that.
As we discussed earlier based on the active profile appropriate configuration is beat up whichever thing
you said that the active profile it will be used to pick up the appropriate configuration and profiles
can be used to configure different kinds of resources.
Right.
I what I talk about an application you'd have application related configuration as well as the resources
that the application Cemex do.
So things like databases queues external web services that you might be using all that might be different
from one.
And we don't mentor another and you don't mind all those kind of things can be configured in these different
files.
And as long as you can figure out that specific profile for that specific environment you are done.
Good what is a profile look at how to create application configuration for a specific profile right
to education configuration for specific profile is created by creating a property for it.
One important thing that you can do with your profile is use your profiles in code to define your beans.
So this dev being here has an ET profile annotation with the value div.
So this being will be only available in the profile div here.
This particular bean will only be available in a profile of Prod. so you can customize.
Even Java Beans will be available based on the specific profile.
While this might be looking like an interesting feature I would actually recommend against using it
because this might if you have been like this defined between different environments that are radically
in your code then your code is becoming specific to a specific and you don't mind.
I don't really like that unless it's absolutely mandatory.
Find a word using this kind of stuff in your code.
In this video we talked about profiles and do the next video.