In the studio let's look at spring board actuate what is being called actuator.
How do you monitor Web services using something good actors.
And how do you find more information about your application environment using springboard.
So there are a lot of things that you can do with springboard.
And in this we do let's look at some of the important things that you can do with springboard.
Actuator is basically an application which you can use to monitor your application with a spring board
or lead you need to do is to add a simple dependency.
So as soon as you added dependencies would start the actuator that's it you'll get all the features
around your services for free.
So it exposes a lot of our race.
It exposes a lot of services.
Slash slash Metrix slash trees dump beans.
Auto configuration can fake props and mappings lets one of the important things with actually it is
the fact that before springboard 2.0 the L was slash actuator.
So it was slash actuator.
Now it's slash application so early as it was earlier it was slash actuator.
Now it's Splash application since Springle 2.0 the uare is slash application.
Let's take a quick demo offspring would actually we are actually using something called a whole browser
to look at this spring boot actuator and if you look at this being boot actuator it exposes a lot of
details in info and we don't let go too and we don't want.
So this shows all the information where the application is deployed.
So you can see what is the question of.
What is the different details that are related to the job of Yemen that is specific to here where is
it installed and also different details related to the Java library the classpath which is being used
and a lot of our environment information is present in the Ian slashy application flash and that's where
this is split.
And other than that the autoconfig has all the information about what configuration.
We looked at it during the auto configuration video.
You can see what are the positive matches what they do match just for auto configuration if you want
to get a heap done.
You can use them if you want but generally get a high level help of the application whether the application
is up or whether the database we are connecting to is up and things like that.
You can go to the head.
So it shows that the state of the application is up the DB status is up.
The kind of database we are connecting to what is the disk space.
How much is free and all that kind of information.
The other important thing is metrics.
So over here you can see all the different metrics about the application at the high level.
You can see information about how much memory is there how much is there and how much how many processes
are present.
What are the threats.
How many classes are loaded.
Details about the garbage collection and the hitch.
DP sessions Well one of the important things about the metrics is actually you can even crack metrics
of your application related to you or else what I'm doing here is I'm hitting one of the highlights
in the application that we have created local OCDE to use this when I'm hitting it a few times.
And also I know that a specific user ID does not exist so that as well.
A few times now you can see an exception response that is coming back in here as well.
So I cause a few errors as well as a few successes.
And now I would go and refresh our metrics some refresh and the metrics out.
And now you can see more details about this thing so user ID.
So we caused a forum for error with the service users.
Eighty seven times.
And this also returned a successful message seven times.
So if I got enough and cause a couple more failures and refresh you would see enough that the number
of failure would have been up so 3:56 user ID is Levan and to do 200 user id remained at seven.
So you can see how many times a specific uare is successful a specific request has failed.
And you can use this information to monitor your application.
So if you are spending a lot of banks then you know there is something wrong with it.
So you can use all that kind of monitoring from here.
So explain to a lot of important metrics idea.
And we don't want as well as about the user application also so all the rest.
So he says your application is exploding.
You can get information off about them using the matrix.
So it's a local host ADHD application metrics logger's gives you more information about what logs are
configured and also gives you more information about the last few requests.
What is the request what is the response that was sent out mapping shows what are the different areas
that are mapped.
So all your press controls all you add error controllers all those kind of things shouldn't be mappings
being shows all the spring beans that are configured as part of your application so you can see that
we have swagga can be mapped.
So this is the Swagel documentation.
This is a bin which causes begin with the swagga documentation so that is present in here and you'll
see a whole host of other beads that are present so you can see all the detail of disappearing beans
that are exposed or that are created as part of application beans.
A dump can be used to get thread dump and conflict properties can be used to look at all the configuration
properties that all the things that you can configure through the application are properties all those
kind of stuff is pleasant in actuator is basically like a management and so it helps you to manage your
application.
You can look at all the different information relating to your information including the application
related metrics and build the next with your boy.