The last topic we got good that we would be talking about is what is command line run.
So if you look at the documentation it says it's an interface used to indicate that a bean should be
run when it is contained within this being application.
This is a little cryptic to put it in layman's words.
This is something you can implement the command line written it and implement a bean.
Then you have to implement something called Amendment that what would happen is the app at the application
startup wants the application Quantic sping application context has launched up then the code in this
method would run.
That's as simple as that to implement a command line.
So you have to implement it.
You have to implement a call command line runner and implement a method call on the arguments which
are passed to this method are the same arguments that are passed to the main method to start running
the application.
So if you are running good application as a job application and there are a few arguments that are passed
the main method to that application those arguments are also passed in to your command line and run
the command line.
Rene is very useful if you want to do something at the application startup you want to populate some
data all you want to configure something.
Those kind of stuff can be done in the command line and run them.
What you are looking at is an example of a command line and this is called the user repository command
line.
And yet all the wiring in a user depositary in here.
As you can see here it implements the command line interface and it implement the arraignment code.
And what we're doing in here is we're saving a few ways users don't so we're creating a few new users
retrieving the user by ID and also doing a find all.
So we are actually doing some simple logic in here.
But the most important thing the fact that all the code.
What are you creating here would run one the application context test launched up.
So if you implement common labor and implement the method which is present in there and run all the
logic which is pleasant and it would be executed at the launch of the spring context within spring but
that's basically what command line that is all about.
So if you have some logic that needs to be done at application startup this would be one of the best
places to implement it.
And then the next week you may.