Welcome to the section on need testing one of the most important features of Spring Framework is it
makes unit testing very simple.
We'll look at examples of that in this section.
Let's start with these questions.
How does building make unit testing easy.
What is more kiddo and what is your favorite mocking green book.
Also things like what is a default mocking Chromebook in spring boot.
How do you Magdi do and what are the different mocking annotations that you work with.
We can group a lot of questions under this category.
Let's look at them right now.
So let's say I have some business I am build which is using a data service.
So what it's doing is finding great deaths from all the data.
So basically there's a construct here some business and we should not bring in here but the method get
find the greatest from all that.
What it does is it talks to the database it gets the data from the data service and from all the data
I get it returns the greatest value back.
So if it gets five elements it will find the largest among them and it will return it back.
That's the business logic.
So let's say this is great.
Greatest business I am alone.
Good find degraders business.
Bill what do you want to call it.
So this is a matter which gets some good data and from the data it finds the largest one and written
seatback that's as simple as that.
So one of the most important things when we write a unit test is we do not really want to talk with
the database so I don't want to talk to the data service because they say it is what Doctor the database
file query and get it from the database.
But that's not good because then you are dependent on the database to be available if the database is
down the unit test would fade if the data in the database changes.
Then also your unit test fails so you don't want that dependency on your unit as in your unit test.
You'd want to do something called marking.
You don't want to talk to the data service but you would want to do a mock of the data set.
So you would want to dictate what the data say we should return and based on it we would write a test.
So if this data is returned to values let's say 5 10 and 15 then this method should return a value of
the greatest of all of them 15 right.
So that's the kind of test that we would want to be able to write.
Then the tests are independent of the database.
We don't really care about the database at all.
So even if they don't in the database Changez databases is down this test would still succeed because
we're not really going to go into the database.
We are using a mark for the data.
So is that is the kind of as splitting enables us to write the most popular marking market book is Marketo
let's look at sping and Marketo together in some of the next examples.
This shows a simple test where we're making use of marking.
So we are doing the test for finding great from our data.
So what we are doing is creating a mark.
So the Marketo framework offers a lot of marking method.
One of them is Mark.
So Mark it's one of the static methods in the more Kito class Mark do not mark date as we start.
So what we are doing is we are trying to mark the date so we class what we're saying is when they say
it is not that all it is called Tovan.
This survey is not really all that is called when this is called then we've done 24 15 and three.
So we are saying data is don't use the real object use the mark and when retrieval data is called the
turn this data back we are seeing the 10:24 15 entry back.
So what would happen when this method is called when data so is that the way they do is call when passing
them walk.
What happens when all they do is call it would return the data which we have populated in here.
That is what the marking book helps us to do.
It helps us to define what each method should return so on this day service.
I'm saying it should return this data 24 15 three.
So when did it last I resorted to the wall that is call it with it and 24:15 three.
And if this method works fine then degraders.
Among them is 24:24 should be returned back to what I'm saying is I'm creating an instance of this business
I am built using the Mauck.
So to deconstruct what I'm sending is not the data is that I'm sending the mark.
So I'm sending the mock object to the same business I am Bill and I'm calculating and finding the greatest
from all data and I'm asserting that 24 is the result.
So this is a very good uniters because this does not depend on the database at all.
We are using a mock and creating an instance of the numbers in the sample and writing a unit test for
that.
So this is a really unique test.
If I talk to the real database the data service then it becomes an integration test that is no longer
unique.
This is a unit test.
We would mark out the dependencies and write the unit test for the business logic which is present inside
this method.
This is an example of basic marking.
The thing is mockable makes it even more easier than this.
The reason why we wanted to show the basic knocking is here we're not even making use of any of the
annotations but Machi to make it makes it really easy when we use annotations.
So there is a rhino called Marquis de.
Netrunner.
So when we ran the unit test with that trainer we can make use of the annotations.
So here the way we were creating a mark is Mark off more data.
So we don't class class you don't need to do that or that you need to do is put at Mauck.
So if you put at Mark this mark is created we had to create the business I am in.
And we had to wire the data as we walk in so we are creating a constructor and passing it in.
That also is not needed.
All that you need to do is put and inject Mock's what the market markets in it or not does it create
a date.
So is Mark for this in on this interface.
And it injects it into the business.
I am Bill and all that we need to do in the test is that there is data that we will determine.
This is called The Return 24:15.
And when business I build or find great from all that is called I said that that equals 24.
This is such a simple unit test too right isn't it.
So this is how we write unit tests for business layer.
So even complex methods like this can be easily tested using annotations in this space.
You can see that I will write a unit test for it within a very few lines.
I mean if I have to create 100 scenarios like this I would be able to easily create them in this.
We do believe that house pre-increment makes testing very easy when you have proper dependences defending
all that kind of stuff.
Unit testing is very easy and we love that market.
And we also looked at how to market data with Marketo.
And also we looked at a few marking and that are present with market until next Tuesday.