Welcome back in this way you look at some of the important concepts you would need to use when writing
unit tests for the Babli.
So in the way of spelling we make use of spring NBC or whatever is called the spring rest frame work.
So in this space we video will take one of the controllers that is present and look at how to write
unit tests for it using the mock NBC framework.
We look at annotations like an NBC test at Moblin and we will also look at how to use on assert to so
that is.
This looks like a very very simple method that we would want at this rate.
There is a pathway you will call it that way the pathway will call question id and we are calling a
service is to retrieve the details of the survey and we are returning it back.
So this is a typical press release method right.
So it gets the details.
What happens is it is done.
The liftoff.
So question back the framework then convert it into J-Zone and returning back to what we get as the
output for this.
So this is just on.
So how do we drive a unit test for this writing unit.
This probably is a really complex thing.
So just for a couple of lines of code in here actually we would write a much much bigger unit test.
How do we do that.
We'll start with the set up.
So the first thing we would want to talk about is the at NBC.
So we would want to write a test for which controller this basic method is in a controller called so
we can roll.
So I'm saying I wouldn't write a verb NBC test for weight control not us.
And I'm saying they should run them.
We will want to create a spring application context and that's the reason why we say we will use Spring
Run metal door glass and we are all the wiring the mock NBC.
So once we Ryden web MBC test we can artwork we'll have something called a mock MVC which is available
we can fire our requests against it.
So what we would want to replicate doing is just like we type you are raised in the browser.
So on the browser I would have to invoke.
So is the way I would need to call it a local host call an ADHD slash survey slash survey ID.
Last question.
So I would want to be able to execute the same you aren't in the unit test.
I can use mawk NBC to exit qued that and also I don't really want to tie up with the deals with the.
I would want to mark this out the Moblin annotation allows me to mark these thing.
So I would want to mark the was out and return data that I would want.
Here we are trying to retrieve just one question so we are saying it is start to retrieve specific question
2 will only get one question back.
So I would want to mark this so it is not a trick question to written one question back and then I would
want to fire the request on mock NBC and check that the result contained Jaison as expected.
Let's see the details of the test.
So we are creating a mock.
Question.
So with a few details and we are saying when so we are resorting to the question is called then return
this more question back to what we are saying is whenever this servicer is right to question method
is going to turn the question and then what we are doing is we are actually building the content of
the request that we would want to send.
We would want to send a request to this hourly rates were slashed so one last question one and we are
also setting an accept type.
So what kind of response do we want.
We would want a J-Zone response so I am setting that as well in here.
So I'm building the request builder in here.
And after that I'm executing the requests I'm saying Mark and we see that performed request builder
and return and this will return the result.
So what I'm doing is I'm setting up the mark and then calling the request.
So I'm making the request using mark and B C and then I'm checking whether the expected response is.
So I would expect a response which contains ideas question description is largest country in the world.
And correct answer is Russia that's based on the object which is pleasant in here.
So I'm expecting the same question in Dasen format as the output for this specific result.
What I'm doing is from the result I'm getting the response and converting it into worse treeing and
checking that these two match.
Whether this expected matches with the content as being in here one of the important things is we are
making use of the J-Zone as a framework to say that these are equal when we compare these two adjacent.
They might be small space differences and also there might be some fields which might be missing.
So just an asset will be easily able to as sold irrespective of those differences.
So if I say just an asset and just pass in the field then it will just check for the ID field and so
on.
If I send ID and description then it takes both for the ID and the description and if I send the country
the correct answer it will check for all these three.
So it will check whether these three values have the these three fields have the correct values inside
the dates on the spot.
We are getting back just an answer it is a very useful framework to assert its own values.
So even if there is an extra space right here or if theres an extra space after description and those
are not really important things synergies and you would want to ignore them all those kind of things.
Gibson is they will be able to easily know and it will only set for things which I specify in here.
So if I'm only specifying a couple of closely checked the values of those attributes inside that is
not just an asset it makes searching just aren't very easy in this small video.
We looked at how to use Mark MVC test to unit test MVC meant that we Lubet What is the use of at MVC
test and addition.
We saw that its foot in here and we specified which we wanted to unit test.
We also looked at what is a mob been used more been in addition to create a mock of the subway service
we looked at all the steps in writing a unit test with mock NBC News just on assert to assert that the
sun is as expected.
This might be a little complex if you have not done a unit test with Mark and C before these are the
important things that you would need to know about writing unit tests using Marcom easy until the next
video.
OK.