This you will write integration tests.
When we write an integration test we would want to launch the application as it does and we would want
to check what response is coming back.
So what we do is we'll make use of and in addition call at test.
We would want to relaunch up the real Third-World.
So the local school board will help me to get the port where the server is running and we'll use distressed
template to execute the request.
So we would want to exude a request and get the response back and so on that.
So this first template is a very useful thing to use in unit tests so that we can create web services
and as well as look at what the response contains.
Let's get started now.
So writing an integration test it's being built.
Is very easy.
All that you need to do is use an invitation call at spring board test and I'm specifying the springboard
Application class in here.
So whichever class has the good application in addition that is the class which we need to put in here
application or class.
And I'm saying I would want to use a random board.
One of the things I can do is specify the part where this just has to be run.
But imagine a scenario where this test is running on a continuous integration.
So.
So if you had code had code up for number and if that part number is used on the continuation and dig
us on the on your integration server then US test would start failing.
I don't want that to happen.
That's the reason why you would say in a random poll we are saying use a board which is available I
don't care which party you are using.
Use any port which is available.
And because we are planning a spring context we use at run with spring loaded for us when we run the
springboard test.
What would happen is it would or the way our Bleacher Report.
So we're asking you to nonrandom great or whatever it runs on when I put an at local to port.
In addition it will auto wired that port in here.
So I'll be able to see which port the application is able to run by putting in at local.
So we'll put annotation on it.
So this will are to wire the port number into the port where you will I can use this to file the request
at a later point in doing so this is the basic configuration.
Let's look at the unit just enough to renovate the unit.
I would want to fire a request to what do local host Colin we show up for the application is running
on the local Lieut.-Col and faultless service last week.
One last question.
Last question.
What I want to send is for this request I want to get decent response back.
So I would want to say that accepte header.
So I'm taking a accepte header in here as application so on.
So am setting the accepte head as application Jason and I'm creating an entity.
When you just want to send a request you don't need to hit be entity but when you want to send a request
with accept headers then you would need chitti be entity HDP entity loves us to create the request with
headers.
So what we're doing in here is we are creating an entity with these headers.
We're using a best dressed template so we're calling this template exchange.
This is the method which we are using to what we want to do is we would want to invoke this you are
using these headers.
So which headers headers are in the entity so we want to use the header call accepte type application
just don't we want to send a get method and B would want the response as a string.
So whatever response comes back it will be converted into a string.
And we would get it as part of our response.
And what we do in the next thing is we'll do the responses or get body to get the content of the response
and we will check if it matches the value which we have in here.
So this is how you do a integration test writer in integration with Carla Allen.
We said they heard about this and we checked whether the values that are coming back are as expected.
So we're using this on a set here.
So we just said it is a very good framework to do so and so it will only the values that we would want
to answer to whatever it will you specify in this expected string.
They will be as we did one of the important documents that we are passing in is false.
We want to be not very strict.
So that when we are seeing fall so we are asking just don't be very strict.
Even if there are links to spaces and things like that don't worry about them.
Just go ahead and match them as well as you can.
So in this small we will get how I would write integration test which spring would be used as a springboard
test and addition to launchpad being good application and be used at local port so that we can order
where the food where the application is launched up so that we can find that request on that report
and be used de-stressed template to fire the request so we use a distressed template to file the request
to the Springwood application and we use just on Isold to check whether the response is expected until
the next redo.
But by.