Welcome to the section on NBC the model view controller in this section we will talk about the applications
and how do you roll up their applications with spring MVC or spelling web NBC in particular.
Let's start with questions related to architectures of that application.
We'll talk about model one architecture model to architecture and model to front Controller pattern.
So what is model one architecture.
What you one is the most basic of the application architecture.
What happens in more than one architecture is in your browser request which comes from your browser
directly.
Code word is speed.
So when would the action bit you put forth your form in the browser would be a JS page.
So the request from the browser would directly go to the GSP all the logic would be in the GSB to handle
that.
I mean you'd be directly calling the database you'd be populating the model.
You'll be able to create the view.
Everything happens inside the GSP.
The thing about the model one architecture is the fact that there are no services which were present
at that point in time.
All that was used was just so at the outset were pages was the only thing which was handling all the
logic and therefore this architecture resulted in very complex JS pieces which were very difficult to
maintain because GSB had all the logic for managing the entire application.
These kinds of applications were very complex to maintain and we quickly migrated to something called
a model do architecture where the request first goes to us of late.
So what happens is from the browser the request goes to a server late and the server let make sure that
it gets the right data and the database gets the moral ready and then redirect it to The View and The
View makes use of all the data from the model and shows it on the screen.
So this was one of the first really clear separation in terms of m v c model view controller so we had
a model which represents the data from the application and we have a view which is like the GSB or the
free market template which I used to show the content from the modem and we had a seed which is the
controller the servlet AG as the controller so they use to.
So if there is a request coming to a service that it would make sure that all gets all the data and
the requests make sure that it's stored to the database it retrieves the data that is needed for the
next page gets the more ready for that and then sends it to the next view so that the view can be rendered
further enhancement of the MVC pattern is the model to for and control look bad and indifferent control
pattern instead of the serviette getting the first request all the requests would first go to the front
controller the front controller is the one which gets all the requests it makes sure that the response
is ready and it would send it back to the browser different controller pattern is very important because
now I have one place to control everything that comes from the outside world.
So let's say if I want to make this application secure I can implement security at different controller
level.
So if I make sure that different controller is secure then my bad application below it is also secured.
That's the flexibility that different controller Papen brings in.
For example the pattern we see that the request goes to different controller controller based on the
request will identify the right of left to execute and also then get the data back from the server let
it decide which view to render and once that was rendered it would send that information back to the
browser.
In this video we got a quick overview of the different web MBC architectures.
We started with model one architecture where there were only EJB just piece model to architecture at
the request from the browser goes to the server directly.
And we talked about the model girlfriend controller architecture where there is something called a French
controller.
And in the next video we're.