Come back in the way you will get a quick overview of the spring and we see frame work we'll talk about
and example control metal in the spring and we see frame work.
How does the flow happen in spring NBC and the different important concepts call your resolver model
model and you and request mapping.
Let's consider a simple screen which is being displayed in here.
So this is a screen with a list of clues which is being shown in here.
If you look at this list of tools there are a list of six truths which we're getting from the database.
When I refresh the page you'd see that there would be six two rows which are coming up and the functionality
which is present on this page allows you to add two rows as well as Update and delete to as well.
The first thing we want to do is display the list of to do so when I invoke this.
You While there are a lot of things which happen in the background as spring NBC is concerned let's
first look at the control method which implements this.
If you look at the control method we are seeing lists to do.
So what is the list to reduce it.
So this is that you are in which we are mapping in here.
What kind of request request method it get.
So basically when you type in or you are telling the browser what happened to or when you click a link
here.
Yes sending a get the quest we would want to handle the GET request to list to do this.
How do you define that.
We define that using something called a request mapping.
So the request mapping is the thing which allows you to map where you are and any type of with the type
of the request here is get something get request of this you should go to this summit.
And what does this method do this method.
What we would need to do is show this page.
Do you think what you're seeing in here is called a view and to display this view.
We need the data.
What is the data.
The data is all the stuff to lose that data is in there are six to do.
So a list of six to do is I would need to get this six to use the data for these two.
Is what is called moral.
So what is happening here is we would need to put the data for all these six truth into the model and
redirect it to would just be what's happening in the background is why not.
Been to you while the request first goes to something called Dispatches So let's not worry about it
right.
No.
From dispatcher sublet the request comes to the controller to this method and this method what it does
is it first calls this service to retrieve the details of all that to do.
So it says OK give me the list of tollbooths for this specific user who has logged in.
And once it gets the details of the truth it puts it into a moral model is what we would need model
is basically the data.
And what we are doing is we are making the model available to the view.
The view is less to those dark days.
So the JCP is the one which will make use of the data we're just coming back to the list of rules which
are coming back.
Just be big and show them in this in this specific way.
When I look at this controller method what it's doing is it can accept requests of this type populate
the model the control method what it does it populates the model and returns the name of the view dening
list to those That's the name of the view to be executed.
How does this name of the view get mapped to the actual view.
How does this list used or does B get mapped to my dsp list to lose or just be just present in webapp
babay Neff views and list Bruce Rogers.
So the controller method if you look at it it's just beginning to lose.
And how does it get mapped to this truce.
Or just be that through something called rezone.
So what happens is if you resolver outbuild OK you get a name then you can append a prefix of flashbulb
last for use.
And the Dodges.
Then what happens is this just the list to lose is displayed.
And in this GSB we make use of the tools which was populated by the controller method and we would display
the content on the screen somebody the control amateur populates the model and it turns the name off
of you how does the enter flow in spring NBC work from the browser.
The first request comes to something called the dispatcher so so the dispatcher servlet in the example
that we were talking about what happens is I'm typing in a huge area.
So first it goes to the dispatcher service that what the dispatcher certainly knows is it knows about
all the controls which are defined in our application so it knows that there is an exception controller
there is another controller there's a welcome controller it knows that what you are told is that a map
to it to it knows that this is the slash.
It knows that there is to do a controller which is present in here which would be able to handle the
different request list to lose and to do and all the other methods which are defined in here.
Dispatcher Sublette knows all the hndler mapping the mapping of controller to you.
It's called a handler mapping Ignaz controller can handle which kind of requests.
So what it does is when it gets this list traduce it will look up Handler mappings to look up the handload
mappings.
OK.
It sees for this controller two controllers.
This method is the right one.
So it will redirect the request to the controller controller.
What it does it would populate the model so that what we see in the previous method it populated the
model with the details of the to do the what does the controller do it populates the modeling.
If any updates to the database need to be made it will make that update.
It will retrieve the data that is needed to display the next screen and what it really did and back
to the dispatcher submit it will return back the name of the view once one dispatcher so that gets the
name of the view.
It will invoke the view resile work.
So it says OK this is the name I'm getting back from the controller.
How do I map it to the view.
So the dispatcher says OK if your resolver mapping to the physical to your name and board there's deputies
and we'll do the viewed as a lawyer would say OK.
Append a prefix and suffix and that you would just be that you need to show and we would land up on
the list to those dark days.
The dispatcher would read it at the request of the view.
With the more the president quitted and the view would be rendered with the model and dispatch it so
it would get the hitch D.M. back and it would send it back to the browser.
So that's kind of the big picture of how the request works in spring and we it quickly the riser to
dispatch.
So that gets the request ignores the handler mappings it finds the appropriate controller calls it controller
execute the request it puts the data in the model and returns back the view name to the dispatcher service
dispatcher that uses the view name and use that the viewers word to map it to a physical view name and
executes the view makes the model available to the view get the hitch DML malcontent and end up back
to the browser.
So it's back to the browser and browser would render it on the screen.
That's kind of the high level flow with being in the seat.
That is one more important concept regarding more and more into bring in because if you look at it there
are two things.
Model map which is typically called a wallet and also more than you which is used as well.
So what is the difference between model and model and actually there is not a lot of difference between
the and the model and when I'm using a model model can only store the data in the model and putting
the data and returning the viewer back.
The other option of having a controller method is to return the model and view so what I can do is I
can create an object called Model and you can set data.
So I am setting data using embedded add objects I'm sending data directly in and I'm also setting the
view Neame welcome and returning it back when I have a preference for this approach.
The approach where I added the view name and populate the Mordred it leaves a clear separation between
the modal and the view but it's more of a mind you prefer and you can use either of them.
For me I prefer this one because it's much more readable.
In this when we looked at some of the important questions related to spring him.
You see we get an example control method which was using that request mapping so the request mapping
is used to map you out to a specific job or control them.
And we talked about the simple flow in being MVC using dispatcher servlet resolver model and model.
And in the next video boy.