Welcome back.
In this video let's talk a little bit about how you can configure your dispatcher so late in the previous
We deal with dog.
Dispatcher So will it being different controller.
So any questions spring NBC would first come to the dispatcher Solet and dispatcher so it would then
look at the handler mappings and be directed to the appropriate control.
And when I'm sending the view back as well from the control I would get the name dispatch table it would
map it to a physical view by using the beautiful word and then exclude the view and return the data
back.
So that basically the entire floor where the dispatcher said.
Right.
So how do you set up a dispatcher.
That's the question that we would discuss.
Now if you look at the dispatcher Sublette it's configured in very similar.
So anywhere we are configuring us of late.
So we are creating a normal service to this.
It should be possible that which is being configured in their product segment we're passing one of the
bad ammeters department is we are passing in is the location obvious pring context where is us in context
present in this application this being context is present at Rabanne of Crucible takes him at this ex-American
paints the bad pring context that is needed to run that web application.
And once you configure the dispatcher dispatcher serviette then what we need to do is to map as you
are able to it here.
Did you at least map to it.
So the other option is to map slash spring NBC or slash EPA or slash whatever you want to be.
So in this first reconfiguration of their backs and then all requests would go to the dispatcher certainly
any request would first go to the dispatcher.
This is how you can figure dispatchers servlet in a typical web application.
However if you are using springboard then you would not need to do this configuration at all because
springboard has this feature called Ardo configuration wherein as soon as you add in spring where NBC
Jard into the class.
But it would see that it would know that you are trying get out of a web application and it would auto
configure dispatches late for you.
So if you are using basic spring unzipping NBC and here's how you do the configuration if you do it
using springboard then dispatcher so it would be configured for you.
And then the next step.
Bewray.