Welcome back in this you we'll talk about form form validation and other such features which can be
implemented with spring NBC.
So what do we mean by a form so let's say I want to update this particular to do so.
I would want to enter some details here and I would want to change the target date to 29.
And I would want to submit this in here what we would need to do is in here we would need to create
a form.
So this is basically a form which contains two fields which are present in here.
The other thing is we want to do in the form is to add validation.
So I would want to add validations which says I would want to at least have six characters in the description.
So this is what is called validation.
I want to be able to implement this validation on the server side so I don't want client side validation
for this.
I would want to be able to implement this validation on the Java side of things.
So in this video let's look at how sping MVC would enable you to do such kind of things will disclose
all the interview questions which are related to these concepts.
Let's start with the first question which is form backing object.
So this is the form right to represent this form in spring.
You would need to have something called a Form backing object.
So form backing object is basically the backend representation the suicide representation of this form.
The table in which this form is map is called the form backing or object or here.
If you look at the control I'm sure to page you're adding an attribute called to do.
So we are saying to do what.
To do that is being added with the default one.
So this is the new page when I go to the Toulouse and say add this is a new page.
So if you look at the description it's empty and the target date is today's date.
How are we getting it.
Because we are adding this as the form backing object we are seeing to use the form backing object.
The details are zero.
I'm also adding a description of him.
And that in today's date as the what would happen is that to do would be written back and Truda or just
be would be shown to use the name of The View.
And if you look at the GSB command name which is used here is to do so we are saying this to do in here.
This object should be mapped to this form so any form the description DSG field to do maps to this particular
description field.
The target date maps to this specific thing.
So we are basically mapping the form backing objects so we are saying this is the object.
And this is how it relates to the form.
And what happens when you click the submit button is we would again map that particular thing to the
to do in here.
So we are mapping it again.
So this is the app to do matter which gets invoked when a pause to happen.
So here you see slash at the do.
And the method is both.
So when the Post happens this basic method is invoked.
And what we are doing in here is we are trying to add that to do so we are trying to get the description
we're trying to add the To Do list of tools that we have.
And then we add rededicating to the list to do speech.
This is the normal flow.
Now we also saw that there was a violation that is getting triggered.
How is it implemented using sping NBC.
What I we need to do is to implement validation.
You need to use something called Jowler validation EPA and the default intimidation for job abolishing
EPA IIS hibernate data.
We're using a few annotations from it here.
So if I want to do validation what I'll do is I can actually go here and say at size and say this description
field should have a minimum of six characters and this is the message which should be shown if that
feeds.
So what we're doing here is we are adding validation to bean directly.
So I wanted to do a class on it to be in.
We are adding a validation.
So this is adding a validation on the B into excises.
One of the annotations which had rallied as far as Jallow abolition EPA is concerned.
And what we would do is on the bean.
So all here what we are doing at valid to what we are saying is we added and at the annotation on that
to do so when data from the form gets mapped.
Here we are saying validated by putting D at the end of.
And one more thing which we are adding in is the binding result.
What happens when I click submit.
Here what happens is that fill up a couple of details is the answer.
What happens is the values from here get bound to this specific method to the to do and what happens
also is that devaluation gets invoked and the result of the validation gets stored in something called
a binding resurged result.
If there are no errors if Brazil has errors then we are redirecting him to the to do page again.
So what we are doing is we are sending them back to the to do page.
There are no errors then we would want to add to do in.
So what we are doing is we added our evaluation on the bean then under control of controller method
we said at the rally and we took the binding result and we did it redirected it to digest.
How do we display validation errors on the JCP it's by using springform bag.
It's by using form Arabs and saying show the errors for that field what field description field.
So what happens is spring NBC would map the error which comes back over here and we would get to see
the validation message in here a little bit of a roundabout kind of thing.
So what we are doing to implement validation in here is be implemented on the bean in the control method.
We would add that really the annotation and the result get stored in binding result we check whether
there are any errors if there are errors.
We did it back to the same page and in the same page we have the form errors which display the errors
in here.
So if you look at validation which is implemented by this being an important concept we talked about
our binding result and also have your map validation details if you will that both of them are binding
result is the result of the validation on the controller.
So the controller it's in that is stored in here.
And the way we display the arrows on the view is by using the form spec.
We also look at some of the springform tags in our view.
Right.
So this is the label.
So this label is whatever is shown on the screen.
Right.
So this is the label which is shown in bold That's the label the input is input field and also the form
input which is present in here so form form is used to create and form some of the important springform
tags are fome fome fome label form input form letters and things like that.
In this video we looked at how do you back a farm using sping MVC using a farm backing object.
And also we looked at the basics of how validations are done using spelling bees and in the next video
we're.