Let's look at some of the other basics which are related to being an easy pathway with moral attribute
and sation it when to use a pathway Deeble It's very simple right.
So you have a huge array to do with Flash 1 and I would want to map it to obey you but I would want
to make it mapped to a controller radio but so here have to do is one of the methods which is present
inside the controller and mapping it to the jewelry.
Slash traduce slash ID so you can see that IDS inside of variable in here.
What happens is I would want to map this one to this DVD.
But in those kind of situations I would use something called.
But really what are we seeing here as part of the quest you are Roy is part Duilia able to hear the
value here.
We would want to take it and put it into our pot.
But in these kind of situations we use and in addition call it part variable.
And the important thing is to declare a billiard ball in this format.
So in the open races close races I put the ID and the ID maps to this part with the built in here would
be in Id get the whole thing and it would retrieve the value of that this week to do back.
So the pathway is typically used in our days as we develop more and more restful.
So it is the importance of pot where the balls increase is multifold.
Actually today when we talk about resources there would be multiple pathway tables in this team you
are aswell.
Now let's shift our attention to a moral attribute.
What are you seeing on the screen is one of the example implementations for a more terlet tribute to
this code which is typically pleasant inside your control.
So instead of spin control you have a method which is annotated with modal attribute and if you look
at the implementation in here what we are passing in is more as the argument and we are adding attributes
to the Mordred we are seeing more a lot at attribute options.
And I'm saying it is don't ask list and that list of options.
So where is the model to be used to disparage Hadad.
Rob don't some very years go into it.
In addition to add description and target date fields in here let's say there was a drop down where
I would want to show the list of values in the dropdown.
So this list of values have remained this theme.
Right.
I don't want to populate them each time into the model for ADD to do abrade to do and all the other
requests which are coming in.
So if I have to do that individually in each of the control method then I would have to have all the
method calls and everything done in repeated places.
So instead of doing that what I can do is use a concept called modal attribute.
So once you define mortal attribute method in your controller this model attribute will be available
to all the methods in that control.
So in all the control the method whether you are doing an act to do whether you're doing a delete to
do update to do or whatever operation you are doing you would have that more attribute available.
And I can use that moral attribute to display the list of values in the drop down.
Here we are populating values of option one.
Option 2 an option to the model attribute indicate that the purpose of that method is to add one or
more modal attribute model attribute method is invoked before the request mapping method.
The dispatcher servlet looks at the uare from the browser and identifies the right control.
And before invoking it it would make sure that the model that butes populate it.
It is typically used to fill the model with commonly needed attribute like drop down values for a form.
The other kind of attribute are Sishen attributes.
You can add a notation called session attribute on your control.
So here I am saying this is an attribute name.
This means that the immortal attribute name so whichever attribute displays in modal bit name of name
it would be stored inside sation as we discussed earlier when we talk about web applications for a specific
user.
There might be malicious people DP requests and to maintain the conditional state we use something called
session.
So whatever attributes whatever attributes that from the model you would want to store in decision you
can define and iteration called at session attributes.
Name For example when I'm using a web application when a user logs in I don't need to get his details
on the database every time I write his name is not going to change in 10 minutes that he spending with
the application or his details will not change for the most part so I can take them.
I can put them in the station and then I can reuse them across the your application this allows you
to do that.
So if you have used the details model attribute I can put it in decision by declaring an addition on
the control local decision attributes and the name of the model attribute an attribute list the name
of mortal attribute which should be transparently stored in the session or some conversational storage.
In this way do we looked at a couple of important concepts to be mortal attributes N.S. attribute.