Welcome back.
One of the tricky things to handle with respect to web applications for most of the day.
Right.
When you look at J.Y. you delete it can store the date and time as well.
And how do you set the default format of the date for the application to use.
So here the target date will be using the m m by Bye bye a format.
Right.
So how do we said that as the format to use and through the entire application.
I don't want to keep saying this for each field in the application.
So if I were one of the options is that if I have 15 date fields I can keep having the condition with
each of those 15 fields.
But that's not good right.
You'd want to be able to handle that in a common way across the application.
How do we do that.
That's basically what we were discussing of counter-proof and you need binder and how do you define
a default date format.
With spring the concept of it indeed bind is an invitation.
So I'm putting in an additional goal and beneath it and in a binder on the specific method and defining
a date format I'm here saying DD m m by way so I'm creating a simple date format and saying for this
specific class for the Date class.
Always use this format.
So whenever you are binding a date field.
So whenever you're binding a date field but when that's binding happen binding happens when you submit
here or whenever you show the form.
Those are the two times when the binding happens it says the need binder what it says is when you are
trying to bind a field of the type would be dark.
So when we are trying to find field for this class use the custom date and the custom date editor uses
this date format which is defined finding here which is DDM.
So this is one of the ways you can actually define your date form and in the next week you will look
at can tolerate ways and see how to make this data format available for all decontrol.