Come back and this we do let's look at how you can implement common logic for all the controllers and
paying him you see.
We'll talk about something called controlled Airways and exception handling is something you would want
to commonly implement across all the controllers.
So we'll talk about it a little bit.
We'll also look at questions like how to handle exceptions for web applications and how do you implement
exceptionality What are the important things to think about as well as how do you implement to speak
error handling for a specific control that meant that what you're looking at in the screen right now
is an example exception controller.
Important advice which is present in here is something call at controller Ed wise.
So this is the annotation that control read is the annotation when you want to implement logic which
is common to many people controllers.
So this is a place to all the controllers which are present in your application and the ways to which
we are specifically implementing in here is at exception handler.
What we're saying is we are defining exception handling for anything of exception class any exception
that happens in the application of exception or any of subtypes would be handled by this method.
So what we were doing in here is when an exception happens in the application in any of the controllers.
It would be handled by this method because we are saying it can tolerate.
Why is it applicable to all the controllers inside the application.
And here we are saying.
Handle exception dark is actually here.
You can also ask with very specific exceptions.
So if you want to say to do not found exception and you would want to handle that separately you can
actually have a separate implementation for that as well.
Or here what we are doing here is actually logging it into the request and returning the error.
So we are saying show the error.
So this will lead to error charges.
So it will go to the error not just be and display the error dogies speak to the user.
This is a web application right.
Whenever an error happened.
What we want to do we want to show an error page to the user.
So this would handle the exception and it would show an error page to the user.
How do you implement common logic for controllers thing and we see that's implemented by using control
of headways control headways is used to implement common logic.
Exception handling in the last VBA will indeed bind.
So we can also use control of advice to implement it bind.
And we look at exception handler with the exception handler.
In addition we'll be able to define how to handle a specific exception.
So if we can limit that is throwing any exception then that's an exception handler helps us to handle
that.
You don't want to have a common exception handling all the method.
And if you want to have specific exception handling then you can actually have the same method as an
in your normally control.
So if I take my two controller and put this method in then this exception handling is applicable only
for this specific controller.
Why don't we talk about exception handling with respect to web applications.
The important thing to make sure is know what happens if you don't show a photo for or something of
that kind to the end user or you do want to show a proper error page and one of the important best practices
is also give him a handle to ID.
So kind of generate a random number in here or a sequence of numbers is fine as well.
So kind of have a sequence of numbers and give him an ID.
And what you can do is use the ID and log all the information you have about that exception in here.
So make sure that the the user gets all the details.
That's number one make sure that the developer has enough details in the log present to handle that
exception.
So those are the two important things you need to think about when you are implementing exception handling
in your applications.
In this video we looked at how to implement common logic for controllers.
We looked at exception handling as a specific example of that.
And next would you say.