In this last week on sping and we would be discussing about why is NBC so popular.
One of the most important things I like about being in the U.S. is the clear separation of concerns.
So you have a dispatcher servlet you have your controllers you have you have your duties all worse you
have your views modelled and views you have your controller side your moral attribute.
You have your station attribute all these are completely independent of each other.
So each of these concepts are handled one thing and they do that really really well.
It helps me to develop a web application very easily as well as it helps me to unit their stuff very
easily as well.
I think the clear separation of Canton's which is being MVC brings in is one of the most important reasons
why spring NBC is really popular.
The important thing to understand is springing busy is not only used to develop applications but it's
also used to daily press with Web services.
So the section on being NBC actually does not end here.
Bill talk a lot about its full web services later.
And during that section we will talk a lot more about putting NBC and also about RESTful services and
then the next we do.