Welcome to the section Andreas Phillips series we'll talk about what is a restful web series What are
the good practices in designing services.
And we'll also talk about some of the most important implementation things surrounding this lip services
spring rest of spring.
Let's get started.
The question is which we would be discussing in this specific video.
What is the rest and what are the best practices for us for that.
So we says rest stands for representational state grants for when we talk about topup services.
We are focused on the format.
We are focused on using soap and we love to paper and so forth.
But rest is a little different it kind of set a few architectural guidelines and that's it.
It does not worry about what format of request you are sending and things like that.
What the rest wants to do is to make the best use of his TTP.
But my feeling was the head of the team which was working on HTP and he came up with this approach called
The rest where he said OK why do we really need to implement another way of doing things for Web services.
Why don't we make use of what we already did.
History put away pro-white all the necessary things to be able to develop good web services.
Why don't we develop an approach where we develop Web services using Hastey.
So when we talk about rest what we're talking about is making the best use of DTP.
The people are white.
Things like HDP equipment third and bit his lip response.
We contained different kinds of state court when we make use of the best possible way.
We make use of all the HTP request methods that are available in the appropriate way and also send the
appropriate hastily peer response status based on the situation with the reserves.
The rest focuses on this important concept call at least source as far as the rest is concerned.
Anything and everything is a sword.
A user is a resource to do is resort a list of users is a sword and you can both form actions on these
resources.
Each resource has something called identifier you a Uniform Resource identifier.
So if I want my first to do the YOU ARE A is users slash longer slash to tools for flash one if I want
to lose the OR for that resources you will slash Runga slash traduce if you want the details of Rangar
then the various users as Runga.
So these are really different resources.
And there you raise the focus for rest is on resources.
So each of these tools has a huge array and also you can pull form actions on these resources.
How do you perform actions on the resources by using the appropriate request method.
If you look at the request method are some of the requests met that there was delete get pulled.
There are others as well like head and stuff but the things which we typically use in restful services
are post delete get and put.
For example if I want to create a user I would say to this uare I would send a post request if I wanted
to delete a user.
I wanted to be specific about which user to delete.
So as a user slash one I want to delete the first user and I'll send the delete if I want to get the
details of all the users get and slash users get the details of a specific user.
Which user are you on to get sort of slashy this slash one and I send a get request to it.
The most important thing about breast is it does not worry about data exchange format.
While design is the most popular one example is also an option to use when we talk about trust.
Actually does not care about which exchange format you use text x images on whichever one you are convenient
with use it.
However the rest is very focused on which three and four.
You have to use HDP as the transport press wants to make use of the best things which happened initially
and therefore the only transport which is allowed is his TTP as far as his definition is concerned first.
There is no standard at all that application definition language Babel is used a little bit over the
last couple of years.
I see that it's losing ground to Swaggart.
Swaggart is not the most popular format.
It's now called open API documentation as well.
So it's picking up pace in the last couple of years.
For now it's kind of the format which is used typically when we're talking about race.
So is this article open API documentation.
In this would you regard a quick introduction to rest next will you.
Let's look at best practice related to rest.