This would you.
Let's look at the best practices in this full web services design.
When we talk about Chris for Web services or any web services for that matter the most important best
practice is think about consumer first understand what your consumer needs what he understands before
you design your s for Web services.
Think about what kind of consumers you might have.
Well it's a web application whether it's a mobile application what kind of consumers do you have and
what is the language that they would understand.
So when you are designing the suitors you send them in a way that your consumers would be able to easily
lead to your resources.
Think about how your consumers would think about it if you're thinking about implementing things like
radios.
Think about how your consumer will consume it before you design ideas for your abs.
The first aspect is always consumer first.
Think about your consumer.
Make the best use of HTP right feeling when he coined the term race.
He said we will build it on top of his GDP and all the rest architectures make the best use of GDP they
make best use of all the history repeat request method like get balls put delete.
You design your resources and make sure that you use the appropriate actually pretty close methods to
perform the actions on these resources.
And also you make sure that you send the right response status back from your sources.
So when I let's say get an exception I'm trying to search for a user and user was not found then I don't
throw us over the exception.
What I would throw is actually is torture not fun.
So didn't did this so out and the response to it as of four or four when there is a validation error
in the request for example I would send a bad request.
It's not a server when there's a validation error.
It's a bad request so you'd send 400 back when there's a post request to create a resort and it's both
successfully completed.
You'd actually send a response to it as of two hundred in one which is created.
So make the best use of what were hasty people are white.
That's the second best practice make use of the appropriate request method send the appropriate response
status back.
The third important best practice is no security information in your race raise in your you I raise
what you're saying is not as securely encrypted as what you send in the body or that request or less
understand that.
So things like SSN do not send it as part of you or you are right even though you might have a SSN as
a key to some person but don't send it as a part of you or you otherwise.
I prefer using plurals to using a single word.
So I prefer you are rules like Slash users so that I can post to slash users to create and you lose
it.
I can send a request to slash users to get the list of all users.
I can send a request to slash users slash 1 to get the details of a specific user.
I kind of like this last user slash user slash one approach compared to this slash user slash user slash
one.
So I like using plurals to represent my resources in this quick review.
We looked at the best practices in restfully design Kazuma first make best use of HTP make use of the
appropriate request method make use of the appropriate response status have no secure information you
need a huge array and try and use plurals as much as possible.
And intellectually over.