Welcome in this we do we would start discussing implementations of Atlas for their services with spring
rest and spring and ribbon we see in this video will focus on the GET request.
So we would want to get the details of a specific sort using spring.
Just how do we do that.
What happens when we do or don't have been adequate mapping method and what is good mapping and related
material.
But in spring at least let's get started now.
So what you are looking at on your screen is a simple gate mapping for Flash users.
In the previous videos which were related to NBC we were talking about request mapping and we specified
Demetriades equal to the equipment that don't get good mapping is a shortcut to that to get mapping.
And that in addition where I'm saying OK I didn't want to say that eques mapping and then say the request
method is equal to this I would rather have a shortcut and say get mapping so good mapping is kind of
a shortcut to the quest Mapping Center to get mapping.
There are other things like force mapping mapping mapping and things like that.
This specific method handles a GET request to slash users and what is it doing it is talking to a service
retrieving all the details of the users and returning it back.
So this is a simple method for a gate is how does this get converted to J-Zone or whatever format of
your response that happens because of something call message converters video using springboard to Delap
here.
As for the services what happens is spinning boot registers message and where it is by default the default
message converter for J-Zone format is Jackson.
So what happens when I return a list of users is it will be converted to Jason and the J-Zone response
goes back in the shot.
We do we look that code for an example you get two thoughts with Pingris.
We looked at what happened when a business returned from a mapping method and we talked about good mapping
ports mapping and mapping and things like that until the next video.
Well Ray.