This would you.
Let's talk about the code for implementing a forced method both method is used to create resources so
I would want to create a resource.
Also we'll look at why we use response entity in areas for.
Let's look at an example implementation.
So here I would want to create a user that I would want to create and you would use it.
How do I create a new user.
We would send a POST request to slash users.
So what we are using is a forced mapping.
So we're using our annotation plus mapping and the uare slash users so this would handle the post was
to slash users.
What we can think of the request is or whatever is part of the content of the requests that get mapped
to the user.
How do we do that.
We are doing that by using the at request body in addition to whatever is the post request content would
be mapped to this user.
So that's easy right.
I want to map the content to the user so that I can create the new user in here what we are doing is
we are actually using the service the state the user details to the database.
So we saved the user details to the database and it turned the saved user.
What is this piece of code doing this piece of code is ensuring that we are relating to the rest full
service best practices.
We know we created it.
We thought that we should send that as status off to all one here.
If I return this save the user back what would happen is this will directly return a status of success.
It would send a status of success back.
But what we would want to do is we would want to send the status of created back as well as you'd want
to send the details of the created user.
What is the new resource that is created.
The neutralizer that is created is having ID off get ID.
So I would want to actually form the you wire of the new resource and send it back to the consumer so
that they can directly access that resource details.
How do I do that.
That is done by using responsa entity response entity.
You can say a status of created to I want to send a state as have created and here I am actually creating
the you Ira.
So I'm saying get to the current request uare at penned this pop to dispatch users Abend slash ID and
replace this template ID with whatever ID is coming back from the database.
So lets add this use I was saved with the database and he gets an ID of hundred.
So lets users slash hundred would be the uare which would be returned as part of the response header.
Let's look at a simple example of a so I would want to post.
So I chose post-master and I'm typing in a local host 88.
Less use.
And in the body and putting the content of what I would want to a name and birthdate and posting about
it in here.
And when you say in this what you would get back is a status of two hundred and one.
And indeed that is the work of didn't you created.
You said you can see the location in here it says location 88.
Slash uses slash.
So that's basically what we have been discussing until now.
So whatever can we put in for the users part of the body is mapped in here at request body and we are
forming the location of the response you Ira that we would want to send as part of the location header
and we're adding a status of created.
So if you understand how it's being fired and what is the response that is coming back and what is the
header location header that is coming back.
It's very easy to directly look at this and relate to what is happening in here.
In this video we looked at how to create resource by using a force request using spinning wrist.
We also at why we need response and we need response entity in this specific example because we wanted
to return a status of created back.
We didn't just want to Britton's taxes.
We want to return a specific status quo created the location of the created resource with the rest of
the created source.
And that's the reason why we used sponte indeed.
And then the next week you play.