This this way.
Let's shift our attention to it.
Hideous what is hideous.
Can you give an example as opposed to hideous.
How do you implement using spinning.
Let's look at all these questions in this specific medium.
What is said to use videos is of Lijah expansion hypomania as the engine of applications.
It is indeed a huge definition.
Let's look at a simple example.
So I'm going to my GET HELP page I'm looking at the list of repositories right now.
So there's a Web page right in the web page.
What we're doing is I'm asking for my repositories.
So what is the page doing it reading me the details of all the repositories which are present in here
as being web services tips that are based templates and a lot of repositories about 34 of them.
Is just reading the data.
It's also retaining the actions that I can perform same thing.
OK if you want to see more details about this being web services repository you can go here if you want
to start this.
You can do it here if you want to for this.
You can do it here.
So it's not just showing the data but also showing the actions you can pull from that data.
So you can start a repository and data repository or or repository or see the detail of a specific repository.
So it's not just retaining the data but also actions that you can perform on the data.
Hideous tries to bring that concept in restful prep so says when you ask for a source don't just return
the details of it so don't just do it then the data.
But also it is done.
What are the actions that can be performed.
What are the other things that can do more of this resource might be interested in.
For example let's take a Facebook for so let's say you are exposing service for fetching the details
of a Facebook post with Heti us what you would also consider returning.
Is it links to things like like how do you like the post.
How do you like the post.
How do you comment on the post and things like that.
Here is an example.
So when we are requesting for a specific user what we are also sending in is the link to get all users.
This is a request to a specific user.
What we are sending is a link to all the users as well we are saying OK this is how you get the details
of our users.
How do we implement this kind of stuff in spring.
Theres a startup which is provided by spring board called Spring boot start ahead the.
So we need to do is we can include this data in and after that we can use a concept called source resource.
You get to return not just the data so you will get to that and not just the user data.
So I can actually read the end user then the data goes out.
But what the source helps us to do is to build on top of that so I'm creating the results using the
user using the data.
So now the data is populated into the resource.
Once the data is populated you can add links.
So here I am trying to add a link.
What do I want to add.
I want to add links to all users.
So if you look at this this is how it would come out.
I would want to have a link with the reference as all users and I would want to have the link to which
the source I'd want to have the link to the tree.
All Users resort to the source which is pointed by the method retrieve all users easily hardcoded the
link in here I get say slash users and hide quoted in here.
But that would mean that any time I need to change the details you Aure or slash users I would need
to also change it in here rather than hard coding slash users directly here.
What we are saying is OK we would want to link to the resource which is exposed by this method by the
method and retrieve all users and we are returning the resource back when we implement it in this way.
You would get a response back as we look at it in this video we took a quick look at hate yours.
We will get an example response for videos and how we can implement it using something until next video.