This would you.
Let's shift our attention to what.
Documenting this for Web services.
How do we document that.
So is this what is the Raguel.
How can we generate back up for restfully web services and also how to add custom information using
swagga documentation.
We like to look at what is dragged away.
Let's get started now.
There are multiple ways you can document your restful Web services.
There is Rabil there is open talks and the one which is popular right now is what is called Swagger.
Swagger is now called the open API specification.
The specification helps us to define the contract for rest for Web services.
You can define what are the.
What are the operations that can be performed before we look at the details of this swaggerer documentation
and the specific format of it.
What we do is we look at how degenerated from our code.
So if you have a restful web service which is built using springboard then you need to do is to add
these two dependencies in.
So you need to add a dependency calls bring Fox ragged to and spring Fox back to you.
I will look at the way first but I get a little later.
These are the things that you need to be able to generate documentation for your full web services.
Once you add in the dependency you can configure a simple swagga config.
Here we are actually enabling this documentation for this project and we think this is a spin configuration.
And other than that we need to create a simple been called a docket.
And we're using Swagel to wash in of the specification.
So you're saying we would want to expose Swagel was not the specification for all of this yes and once
you do this you'd be able to see swaggerer documentation for us so users in this format will understand
what in artist go through.
When we look at the high level these are the important elements which represent in as good documentation.
You think you're using swagga 2.0.
That's the question of the specification we're using the input bag contains the high level information
about our EPA what kind of EPA up your footing and that kind of stuff.
And the host is where we are hosting the service or we are hosting the EPA.
The best part is the base.
But if the base part is slash EPA then to call the services you need to use close the ADT slash.
And that's something which you can use to group your resources so for each of your resources and resource
methods you can same bags and bags can be used to group your resources into multiple categories or things
like that but include the details of all the resources that we are exposing and the different operations
that can be performed on each of these thought this definitions include the different elements that
are used in our EPA for example.
What does the user contain what are the different elements inside the user.
What are the different elements inside the hello world.
That's what is provided by the definition.
It's very important that we need to dig in for parts and definitions.
Let's do that right now.
So what is info contained in detail it contains a description of your API.
So here I can see this is my awesome EPA and a high level overview of what kind of things that we are
doing probably here we can say something like we are exposing the EPA for a social media application
and high level information.
And that wasn't the situation of the EPA.
You're exposing in here you can do it title.
And if there are any terms of services that you have you can put it in here and you can have a contact
person you can put the details in here as well as the license.
So the default license which is present in here is Apache 2.0 that you're in for attack.
The most important ones are inside the box contain all the resources that we are exposing.
We created a lot of hello world resources.
Those are here other than that the most important ones are the user resources so we have resort to exposing
all the users.
And also we have a specific user to do so as well.
So this one the user flash IDs a specific user.
So you were trying to get the details or delete a specific user.
And here this is group of users this really sort of exposes a group of users for a specific user.
Let's begin the users folder.
When I go inside you would see that there are two operations which can be performed what are the options
get and post so you can get the details of all users or you can use the post-operation to create a new
user.
What should we doing to get the operation into get operation.
You can see there's a summary and operation Id We think we can do an application design and produce
our daughter in the next step.
We look at how to customize this actually we can consume both applications as well as application X-Men
and we can produce applications.
So nice to see priggishness sentiment and also what are the different responses that we can give so
you can see that we can provide a responsive 200 when it's success when we would say 3:56 when it's
not found when there is a user ID password or when authentication details are not really provided.
What do you do.
Send a photo.
One thing you are an interface to access this is when we look at the success so the 200 there is a schema
definition which is pleasant in here we think we will find in every area of what area of use.
Thats the thing which is returning back what we are defending in here is the Spawn's would contain an
array of users.
Where is the user present the user is present in definitions.
I can go to the definitions here and click that and you'd see that user is defined in here I can click
user for folder and see the complete definition for user id seen.
But the date string date then Id integer and a name so user content these properties at a high level.
But define what are the two sources that are exposed for each of the resources you see.
What are the different operations that are allowed and for each operation we would see what it consumes
what it produces.
And what are the different responses that are present.
In addition for possed requests you will also have Bajrami.
We have.
I mean how was it sent it sent as part of the board to your daily quest for the post request for Flash
users accept the input of pipe users inside the body of the request.
And also we are saying it's required because without that there is no use to send a request.
If you don't send the user the data.
What is the use of signing up for request.
The other resource which is X-post is best if you use it right.
Let's use that slash ID on this.
What are the operations that we are following.
We are having as of now or get an A.
Let's look at delete you'd see that the country owns produces almost the same.
What we are saying there is a bad meter.
There is one parameter.
Its called ID of type integer but its sent in the bar.
We are differentiating it here.
So here we are accepting it in the pot.
However in the fourth request How should the details be sent inside the board in Sabbat ammeters in
body imports requests what do we do.
We put the content as part of the body of the request and in the delete and to get the space recusant
where do we put the ID.
ID is inside the box.
So parts of Defense resources the different operations and the details of each operation and definitions
define what are the different kinds of objects that are being used.
These definitions are used in the different operations exposed by each of the sort.
When we are doing a great operation on this last year we would return back a list of to this resource
of users is what we are sending back on the Get operation on a specific user or here.
You're saying it's sort of you use it.
What is the difference between user and resource user.
The resource that contains additional links to be defined hit earthlings to Haiti or Serling's.
Right.
So those links are added in in the resource of the user type.
So it contains link and definition of the link is also present in here.
As we discussed earlier Ligon campaigns are real and hedged.
If so Drell is all hype and users and hitched up is the actual link to that particular resource.
When you want to expose the swaggerer documentation to your client there are two ways you can actually
download this as a surrogate or just on and send it out to your client.
Or you can use something called swagga.
Q So I'm going to do you at a local host Aidy this baggage you've got the mail and press enter and then
this is why for all the operations that are being exposed so I can click use a resource here to expand
operations in here.
You can see the different resources and operations that are present so we can see that the user return
is exposing get less users less users delete a specific user and get a specific user.
And if you do want to see the details of those you can click it and you can see what is the response
and what is the schema for the response.
And you can also see what the different response code that you can expect taking a step back.
So I would want to share my documentation my documentation my documentation with my consumer so I can
go and save this Jason or I can see and share this with my customers or I can share the link to my swag.
To either of these will not be a bad idea.
One of the things which we can also do is we can consolidate the details of all the resources which
are split into multiple locations which are exposing resources we can actually have one place where
all the documentation is consolidated and exposed to using the swagga way the documentation that we
can read for those sources.
Very important because this is what our consumers will look at.
If you look at the documentation right now it's not really perfect.
We'll try and improve it a little more so that the customers all the consumers of this of these would
be able to understand the service much better.
So let's say I would want to say the default contact is so and so so the contact information for the
API is to enter.
So I can define a default on taxing them in 28 minutes and my email ID and also I can say the default
EPA in four as well.
I can't say how I would want to actually use AP.
Awesome EPA title awesome EPA description and I can define what is the license which needs to be used
for these abs.
And also I would want to configure the default producers and consumers producers and consumers a little
later as well.
So for now it were going to produce an bazooms to application just on application examine what we can
do is we can use this in the dark to earlier we just defined a simple Dockett But now we are extending
it we are saying OK I would want to use this API in full.
I'd want to use this.
Producers were just present in here and I would want to use the consumes altar as the default producers
and consumers from here.
So we are extending the docket both customizing the information which we would want to show if you refresh
the paradox now you would see whatever customisation we have done sure will show up in the description
to May a description or so maybe it did the contact details and the license as well.
If you go a little below you would be able to see consumers and producers in the formats that we have
specified in a cord.
So anti-law will be a couple of things right.
We just needed to add it added dependency couple of dependencies and then we need to configure swagga
config.
This would give us the basic documentation and if you wanted to customize it to our needs to our specific
needs then we can use things like this to customize the docket.
Swagger also offers a lot of annotations to add details about your model.
But if you want things like validations to appear in the documentation then you can customize the messages
for that.
Here we are adding a moral property saying name should have at least two characters.
So what we have in here would also appear in this record documentation.
You see here that for user there is a description saying name should at least name should have at least
2 characters for the rest of the stuff.
There is no documentation and search for name.
There is a description the name should have at least two characters one of the important things that
we would need to think about when you are talking about this.
So have your consumers would be thinking about your documentation.
So if you just put name they don't know what is the validation message on the name.
They should know what is it they should have details of the different relation which is which represent
those kind of stuff.
You can add in using your at API model property in addition.