Welcome back in this we will talk about presentation of what we saw.
The rest is all about resources and good representations.
What is representational for this sort.
What is a negotiation.
What is the history behind it which is used for negotiation.
How do we implement content negotiation using string boot and also how do you add support for example
in you address for Web services.
Typically this provides services use this on format but if you want to use Excel for Mac How do you
do that.
OK lots of questions but actually the answer for all of these is are very much related to what we are
going to do now.
Let's go to our favorite U.K. postman and fired a couple of requests.
I'm fighting a GET request to local host ADHD slash users and clicking send and getting the details
of users.
What is the format in which I'm getting the response back I'm getting it in the format of J-Zone right.
This is just on format.
So how did we decide on actually Menudo up something with springboard.
It's the default.
So when you have the press will be upset with this spring but the default message converter which is
used is just on Jackson.
Let's say I would want to have XM respond back instead of Jason.
How do I tell that to the Szilard typically HTP has this thing called accepted or accepted it else.
I'm saying that it was way too.
I'm saying I would want a similar response back so the way I can specify it basing application slash
exam.
That's the response I would go on to get back.
Now I click the send now I'm getting a response back in XM and now if I say it is on what form does
it come back it comes back in just on when I'm saying in it's coming back in a similar format.
The great thing is not just this but you can also send post requests using ex-model format.
I can't say I can take this and actually send a post request as well so not just this but I can send
a post request.
The body content is application Semmel.
And Adam is already there.
I don't need to send an ID so I'll save it for Adam Adam too.
And file this request you'd see that you get a response back of two or one created.
And when I send DID IT GET request to this.
You can see that at the bottom of the screen there is Adam 2 who is added in what we have been doing
until now is instead of using Jason as the format we were using application except mid-last the format.
So when you were sending a request we were sending it and accept Hayder call application exam and then
we were sending a post request what we would be sending is a header called content type.
We are saying the Content-Type I'm sending in this application ex-inmate this thing which we are doing
is called content negotiation what we're sending to the server is that I would want a similar response.
I would want just one response was telling that the client is telling that to do so.
The awesome thing is their server is able to understand that and be able to send their response in the
appropriate format.
Now let's go back to the set of questions that we had.
So what is the representation of the source.
When we talk about users use this is the same.
The resource is the users.
What we are seeing in the responses is the presentation of the resource the similar presentation of
the desert or just on the presentation of the text.
So the representation is basically the format you are using to represent your resource What is content
negotiation.
In the earlier example we saw that when we sent this I was responding back with similar response when
we sent Jason as the accepted her.
So what was responding back with Jason and that is basically what is called in negotiation is a negotiation
which happens between the server and declined declined saying I want it in this format.
And so we're sending the response back in that specific format that is Campton negotiation which he
hit his head.
Was put into negotiation.
Typically when I'm sending a request I would use accepte head.
So the accepted Spaceways can then type that I would expect for the response.
How do we implemented with using spring boot and how do you adek Semmel support both of them have the
same answer it.
It's very simple to add ex-MIL support to your recipe webservices which are built using spring build
all that you need to add is a simple dependency Jackson data format a simple one to add this example
in springboard would automatically configure the X M-L misstates can word that in this way we focus
on content negotiation.
We talked about representation of the source.
What is the history behind that which is used for content negotiation and how can we implement ex-MIL
support for us for that.
So is this using spring and didn't actually go away.