You take them back in the studio.
Let's shift our attention to exception handling exceptionality is one of the most important things you'd
want to really do well in your work.
He.
So we we'll discuss questions like How do you implement exception handling for us.
So he says What are the different areas that you would return.
How do you prevent them using subring boot.
And also we talk about validation.
How do you prevent relationships with restfully that services for us.
Let's look at the response to this is that you would want to read back when any of these request is
successful.
Let's get to Questar you you'd want to return to it as opposed to create resources.
Successful you'd want it done well and created that normally does this strike all the remaining things
a response it says when you don't know what went wrong then you can do it in 500.
So what if that something went wrong on.
So how would you know that the resource is not fun so somebody is searching for a user ID and it's not
phone in those kind of situations you should not do it on a server but you would want written up.
So smart phone somebody sends in a bad request with a validation error.
You'd want to send a bad request at somebody sent a wrong ID and password.
You have to send a portal one unauthorized.
So you should send the right response status for the situation that you're in.
In this video we look at to respond straight as we look at 3:56 research not found and 400 by request.
So it's just not found is when a research is not found when I'm trying to search for an I.D. and the
I.D. does not exist and cursed is when there is isn't.
Let's see how we handle them in this specific area.
So it started with the foot of foot it was not fun.
I'm searching and Finian get this.
If you look at the code that we have here it to retrieve user actually throws a user not found exception.
So what is happening here is the default spring boot exception handling is kicking in.
So spring boot on Figaro's error handling by the fall.
So what happens is when you throw any exception when we throw or use a not fun exception with ID ID
what is happening is an error response of this kind is being seen back.
One of the important things to note is status is 500 to the response status.
We're just coming back is upstaters 500 the thing not found Id find it.
Users find it this is good but I don't like the fact that it is returning and sponsored us 500.
What should we it done.
So it is not that we would want to return a status of resource not fun.
How do we do that.
We can do that is by adding an invitation on top of yours or not fund accepted.
You can say HGTV say it is not fun.
Or sponsored a Saturday to start.
Not fun.
What would happen.
You'd get a 4 or 4.
So this is pretty cool right now we're getting or status and that's responsible that perfect because
this is not fun.
Now one of the other things we would want to also do is to customize the response structure what our
response structure is coming back is the default response structure for spelling would help.
You might have an organizational specific standard error message structure you might want to customize
this to us for sure.
So how do you customize that.
Let's say this is a structure that I would want to customize it to have a time stamp message and the
kids.
So if I want to get error messages in this structure how can I do that how can I get my error messages
in my organizational organization defined standard format.
How do we do that.
The first thing which we would need to do is to define exception response so here we are defining a
simple bean exactly matching the structure that we would want to did with a time stamp delimited message
details.
Am I missing the detail here as well.
The second thing we would want to do is to implement our custom exception handling.
How do we implement our custom exception handling one of the things putting NBC pro-white is something
called the sponte indeed the exception handler.
It has the default exception handling implemented in there.
What we can do is we extend that.
So we'll extend the response into the exception handler to provide a customized response entity exception
handler and B does the rest controller because this would handle all of situations we would want to
do all this stuff which you typically do in a controller here but maudling in terms the other situations
and we are adding an annotation that can pre-load ways because this applies to all the controllers.
Now inside the customized response entity exception handler.
What do you want to do.
We want to create an instance of the exception response.
So what we're doing is you are creating an instance of the exception response and returning that back
with the status of internal so and that's basically what we are doing we are saying we know there's
an exception to an exception handler exception to any exception have print handle it and return an error
structure with this response back.
That's cool too.
Any exception of.
We are now threatening our own exception response object back which we have defined earlier.
So this is the exception response object which we are reading back here.
You can get a lot of other details from the request and the exception.
So if your organisation needs more details then you can customize it using what the word values represent
an exception as a verb request which is pleasant here.
The other thing is you don't really want to read them in the OR WHATEVER.
Always say time for specific exceptions you'd want written status is based on that particular ever for
example for the user not found exception.
I would want to read them not phone.
How should it be status not phone.
So here I am defending an exception handler for the use of not found exception to.
In addition to this method to handle handle exceptions I'm adding that call handle use or not found
the exception.
Now what would happen when you use an exception occurs within a hash GTP status of do not found and
exception response of this.
However for any other exception we will be turned back.
We will return in two minutes or whatever with this exception response back until we look at how to
handle food or food or smartphone.
We found a way where we actually put on an addition on top of the exception and as we can create a customized
structure by defining our own exception handler.
We looked at both those options.
The next one is 400 bad because two and there is about lation what we want to do is here somebody is
trying to create a user by posting this object structure to flash you through it.
I don't want to love names with less than two characters and similarly I don't want to have a birth
date which is in the future.
So I would want to add those two validations in.
How do I do that.
The way I can do that is by using our validation EPA EPA has a lot of annotations which you can use
to specify validations on your beans here under use I mean I'm saying there's a violation called excise
mean is equal to two I'm saying names should at least have two characters similarly but I'm saying at
last.
So I'm saying but they should always be in the path.
This is how you add validation to do you begin.
Once you add validations onto your being you can add the invocation of the validations onto you or the
source.
So in your research when somebody is calling a post request you want to do the binding and you want
this validation.
What we would do is we would add a valid annotation to be created with a post mapping for Slash users.
We are adding in rallied to the request board.
So now when somebody first request this what happens is first the validation on the user get fired.
These validations which are defined in here get fired.
And this would throw exception.
What kind of exception does it throw throws something called a method argument not really the exception.
So what this does is when the binding happens and the binding does not match what is needed when some
of the violations fail.
What it does is it throws method argument not valid exception.
So we are actually now extending custom exception handler to handle these validation errors as well.
When there's a validation error we would want to return the status off bad request.
So what we're doing now is it should it be said as a bad request.
And we are retaining the binding result back.
So we are actually looking at the binding result binding result is the result of this validation to
when the validation is invoked whatever errors are coming up.
Are stored into an object called binding.
Said we get the details on the binding result and send them back to the user.
How did they respond to look like in this kind of situation.
So when I'm sending a request with validation errors I would get back a 400 status bad request saying
validation failed.
The details are so and so it's saying name should at least have two characters.
You cannot have a name with just one character.
And this is perfect because the customer declined in Woking So it has a clear idea about what went wrong.
So he wouldn't also can take the message from here and handle that properly.
And this we do we looked at implementing exception handling for Phillips series's.
We did the different Arab citizens that we can retain as well as how we can implement validation errors
in RESTful services and in an extremely low birth.