Come back in the studio let's discuss about the worsening for us.
PHILLIPS So he says we'll discuss why do we need the training what are the options that are available
and how do we implement them for us for that.
So he says let's get started now.
Why do we need versioning.
Let's say there was a first version of this service person with which was implemented just one field
for the entire name.
This was good for the initial versions of this.
And after a couple of years we realized people would want actually to be able to store first name and
last name separately.
So we actually needed a second version of this service with the first name and last name upgrade.
I cannot have just one version of the service because the users of the first version of the service
will not be able to consume the second version because I'm changing the structure of the US bonds earlier
name was in a specific location.
But now I'm actually splitting it up into two fields.
First name and last name and the structure of the response changes.
So what is the first question of the server is will not be able to use the second version of the service.
So I would need to now definitely have two different and two of these services.
Now how do I handle scenarios like that.
What are the different versioning options that we have that what we would discuss now the first two
options of versioning are more related to you as you are right.
So what I can do is I can have Beaven and we do slash person.
So here we are using the you are right to separate the two.
Bush and the other option is to use request paramita questioning so you can pass devotion as a request
paramita question is equal to one and Bush is equal to two.
Next option of versioning is called Haydar worsening in the header.
You would send a bad in the requested or you would tend to permit nothing except what I would want one
a separation.
I would want to the fourth option is to use a MIME type or accept header versioning here.
What we are doing is we are sending something called an accepte head.
So we expect the client to send and accept Hayder of this if they want to use the version 1 V-2 if they
want to use the wash.
So these are our before washing options.
One is by uare the next one is by request paramita.
The third one is the a header and the 12:56 is accepted.
Now how do we implement this.
Its very easy right.
So if I want to implement you or I were shining I can just say V-2 slash person and I would be able
to implement it here.
We want it to be as simple as that.
So now in here I am listening V-1 and here I am returning to the service know if I want to use reckless
paramita Wishnie then I will need to say Batum So this is how you can do this in spring NBC is a tribute
for the Get man thing called bantams you can the first version is equal to 1.
So this method is in-wall only if you get a request with paramita version of that you will one.
So similarly in your get mapping Batum is equal to wash and is equal to.
The other option is to use the header the references with headers interrupt padam.
I would want to say that.
So I'm saying that is equal to x A B version is equal to do.
Hey that's.
Except exit question is it.
So if you get ahead there is a question with a value to then this response is sent back.
There was this response to send back the other option is to use produce.
So here we are saying this method produces an output of this type in the request.
We put an accepted rule of this type.
Then we'll get this response.
Otherwise we'll get this response back.
This is also called MIME type or accepted a wish.
Let's look at invoking this right now.
So I'm trying to get requests to be one person.
You will see that it's getting Charlie back pop chali name is one and we do.
It gives me the split first name and last name.
The other option that we talk about is by using a paramita.
So here we are using a paramita question is equal to 1.
And here Washington is tickled to hear you get devotion to the request.
The other option is to use the header.
Right so we talked about the header option header.
I'm sending a header back header.
What's the header that we want to use X API.
So I'll copy this here.
Except you word shown except the question is one will get the version one.
Except the question is to get wash to do so.
And the other option which will do that is to use the producers that the mime type produces.
I don't need this code but I would need accepted it.
I'm saying I would accept a response of type which is present in here.
So I'm copying this in executing.
So now I'm getting one of the response I'm getting to have the response right now.
So what look at is the four different options.
These are four of the different options that are present to wash us for the services what you are looking
at on the screen is some of the big organizations where each of these versions are being made use of.
You can see that immediate I versioning This is the accepted or worst thing is use it.
Good Hope washing is use at Microsoft you are wishing is using Twitter experimentor which is used in
isn't actually the thing is all these four methods of worshipping all these for IDs of washing your
abs have their advantages and disadvantages.
So you have to evaluate them for us.
We can because there are a lot of factors that you need to consider before deciding your washing approach
things like you are a pollution misuse of SATB headers because the options 3 and 4 that we discussed
using the HDD behaviors tend to misuse the history.
DP It is because the behaviors were not meant to be used to watch when you were a POS.
You should also think about caching if you are distinguishing US-Soviet versions based on his UDP headers.
It might be difficult to cache them.
The other factor which you need to consider is the kind of consumers you would have if you have a lot
of non-technical consumers who are executing requests on the browser then probably should go with the
simpler option of not using D.H. should be hated and the last important factor you need to consider
is also API documentation.
So how are you generating the documentation and how do you want to include versioning entire API documentation.
The summary is that there is no perfect solution.
You have to really evaluate the washing options based on your needs and make the right choice for you
until the next real way.