Welcome to the database can it do D.S. of this course in this section we would be talking about different
things related to JTB see splinted A B C and G B as well.
We'll start with he and up TVC and slowly we would move on.
JP Let's start with the questions on JTB see what is being JTB How is it different from JTB see what
is JTB template and what is a road map.
So these are kind of at a high level the most important concepts related to Singhji.
So let's start with something that divisi This is basic JTB see that you are looking at the screen right
now.
So what I want to do a simple update I'm creating a query that's number one to write a query create
a prepared statement and then set all the arguments so I'm sitting I would want to said the user has
this description as this or that is being done in here.
And I want to set the time stamp I would want to set the boolean to do is done and then at the end we
have IDs called The question mark so I'm setting 5 to do it or get Dady and statement or you insert
it or close connection or close.
So what we are doing here in typical DBC is we're getting a connection creating a prepared statement
executing the query populating the parameters closing the statement closing the connection.
And what I'm not showing in here is the try catch around this because the Execute method would throw
exception to it.
So check the exception.
So what would happen here is a few methods in here actually through a checked exception.
So you have to handle them.
So around this method you would have a try catch block and make sure that the statement and the connection
are closed so that all the logic you would need to do to execute a slim pull update in JTB.
And that's what a lot of code just to do a simple update what he does is it makes it very easy to do
that kind of stuff.
It creates some.
It offers something called a database template which has a lot of simple method one among them is updated.
So if you want to do an update if you want to exude an update then all that you need to do is database
it simply don't update and use the update query so the query is in here.
That doesn't change so you have to still write the query.
So you write the query but setting the parameters becomes very easy.
So all that you need to do is end the list of parameters in the order in which the question marks.
Is the question mark this becomes the first one.
First question one second one second question mark.
And so on and so forth you can look at doing a delete in here.
So JTB said that did delete from two Dugard is equal to.
And this idea gets Mablean here.
So it is a template.
All the complex logic gets eliminated the logic becomes really really simple.
The other important advantage of DBC is it makes all the check exceptions which are pleasant in here
into runtime exception that is unchecked exceptions.
So you don't need to do any exception handling so you.
Number one it reduces the number of lines of code it reduces the complexity in doing it b c it removes
the need for you to do all the exception handling as well.
One more important concept that you need to understand when talking about being jaded is the concept
of road map.
But what we are doing in JTB is mapping your beans to the table.
So you want to dig the data which is in your bins and store it to your table or the opposite.
So you want to retrieve the data from that.
Right.
So the roadmap would help you in doing that.
So if you had been named so let's say there's a being called to do.
And your bean names exactly match with the database column names.
Then you can directly use a bean propertied or a map.
So you don't really need to do individual definition of what property maps do to what field in the database
so he had ID maps to id feel so use that maps to use it description maps description.
So Target date maps target date is then maps done.
So there is a discrepancy in the terms of ease done mapping to done.
So that's the reason why I had to create a specific road map but this is creating a map but the great
thing about creating a road map is once I create a road map like this I can be use in multiple things.
So here I'm getting the truth for a specific user I'm using to map it.
And here I'm getting it to do for specific ideas so specific to do and I'm using dabru map but so the
logic which we defined in here in the road map can be used.
So there are two basic things right.
So if the column names and the bean property names matches you don't need to do a definition like this
or that you need to do is to create a bean property or map but defining the name and you can skip creating
the entire thing.
But if they don't then you have to create a bean like this to do the mapping.
But either way you can use whatever logic you have created in the mappers in executing the queries this
is one of the other method which is present in JTB see dimply query and query for object.
So here we are waiting for multiple objects.
So here we are actually creating a single object.
So we are trying to get specific to do in this step.
We looked at ping JTB and we understood how it is different from B C We also talked about JEDEC template
and also we talked about road map as well.
The most important difference between JTB and us being database is the fact that springiness is much
more concise.
So you'll have you don't need to do all the exception handling that is typically needed with TVC and
the other important thing is also the fact that you don't really need to manage your restored connections
JTB automatically take the gate off them so there is no need to do things like statement or close connection
that rules and things like that.
So with JEDEC them there's a chance that there is a resource leakage if you don't implement this code
properly but it's been very busy there is no chance that you will make a mistake because we don't really
handle that at all.
All that is taken care of by the GBC template itself.
Those are the important things that you would want to know.
And then next up.