Will come back in this we do a let's shift our attention to it to be able to understand what is GPA.
Why do we need it.
What is hibernate.
How is how does hibernate compared with GP.
And also we would move into things like defining an entity and what does an entity manage it and the
persistence context.
Let's get started with JP.
JP stands for Java persistent EPA.
So why do you really need JPA.
In the previous examples we would have seen simple queries that we were writing right into being JEDEC
and VC we were writing a lot of Kuwaiti's why these queries look very simple in big applications with
hundreds of tables.
These queries were really complex to write applications where there are hundred lines hundred and fifty
two hundred lines of queries.
These queries become very very difficult to manage.
The other thing we need to understand is the guys who are writing these queries and John Howard devlopment
because these queries are part of your Java code and these Jawa they will oppose might not be experts
on the database.
So how do we expect our older players who are expert more on object oriented programming to be able
to write queries for the database.
That way the concept of GP comes in GP defines the mapping from a Java object to what they build.
So how does a job object map to a row in your b.
But that what you would define in GP.
So Gibeah provide a lot of useful annotations where you can define the relationship between your classes
and the birds.
How does an object of a specific class map to a row in a specific table.
Once you define the mapping hibernated that's basically AJP the implementation will be able to create
the queries so that you'd be able to talk to the database.
So instead of you creating the Kuwaitis what we would do is we will do the mappings and the J-P implementation
would create queries for us.
Now what does hibernate Hibernate is a JPA implementation.
Think of it like an interface and an implementation JPA is the interface.
JPA defines what is the annotations.
And once you make use of those annotations we can use Hibernate to make sure that all our additions
are properly implemented.
Let's now look at how to define an entity in Jaypee.
How do you define an entity in JPA just by putting an ad entity on the table so there isn't an additional
entity.
Just put it on your bean and then your bean becomes an entity then it would be managed by GP.
The important thing is along with identity you can add in a table in addition here the class name and
the table name of the same.
So this was not really needed but if the name of the class is different from the name of the table then
you would need an add table and addition as well.
And here we are actually saying this field is an ID and we are asking hibernate to generate a value
for this specific field to hibernate or to generate value for the ID field and for all the other columns
we are not adding any mappings because the name of the column here in the table will match the name
of the field here.
So the name of the column is the same as the name of the field.
Then you would not need to do any mapping Otherwise you can provide add column mappings as well.
What we are doing here is basically mapping your class you're being class to a table in your database.
Once you map the columns it becomes very easy to do the update using DB You are late you need to do
is to use something Gollin in the manager and do a mode.
So here we are doing an update to do so to do the update to do all that we need to do.
And did the manager merge to who created the query for us.
The implementation of GP so the implementation of GP would just hibernate here.
Look said the entity and it knows that.
OK to merge this bean into the database or to save this value to the database it needs to write the
query needs it understands what kind of query it needs to write and critique it and write it and for
the query to the database.
So the main advantage of GP is that as a developer you don't really need to worry about writing the
queries or let you need to do is define the mappings properly and be able to take off generating the
queries for you.
The J-P implementation will take care of generating the queries for you.
Once we have defined all the entities using the identity and things persistence contex is the one which
is used to manage all these entities so whatever changes which we are making to the Ds have to go through
something called up persistence contex actually the baby can access the information in the persistence
context is by using something called entity manager.
So if we look at the entity manager interface which is present in here it says interface used to interact
with the persistence context there are a lot of methods.
Inside you are indeed the manager.
So if I open up the different methods which are present in here.
There are a lot of various methods which are present in the entity manager.
There is a method called merge.
That's the way in which you made use of earlier.
And also there are very kind of bind methods to be able to help us find entities.
So if you are searching for a role then you can use find.
So you have both this method merge method remove method.
You have Find method as well and a very fine at that which I present inside the manager.
You can use all these methods which are present in the entity manager so that you can actually obviate
to do so if I want to update or instead to do then I can use entity manager mode if I want to delete
it to do then I can say entity manager to remove if I want to search for that to do I can use entity
manager dot find and search for a specific to do in this way.
We looked at the basics of GP but neat.
How do you defining D What are the different method to present in the entity manager and what is the
persistence context.
In the next what do we look at more advanced concepts related to JPA.
Until then we.