Come back from anti-d's we will shift to relationships and this WE you will look at how do you map relationship
in JPA What are the different types of relationships.
How do you define one to one one to many to many relationships in GPA.
There are the kinds of relationships which isn't like one to one one to many and many to me.
Look at a few examples for this and look at how to map them using GPA in this specific video.
The first type of relationship that we would be talking about is one student right.
A student has a passport and a passport is associated with a single student.
Right.
So this is a perfect example of one doing so in the past but there is a relationship with one student
and student.
There is one passport.
So how do we create one to one relationship between them be used in a dish and called at one twin here
racing at one twin.
And here we are saying one to one most important thing is to define where the car loan would be created
with a passport ID column be created in the student.
Or would a student ID column be created in the passport.
For that we would need to define which would be the orning side of the relationship here.
What we are trying to do is we would want to have a passport ID in the student.
So what we are doing here is putting an attribute called Map pre-buy is equal to passport if the map
is equal to passport what would happen is the passport ID would be created in this true identity but
also in the Student table there will be a column called Passport underscore ID and that passport ID
would be used in the passport be able to store the passport details.
So we would map the student to up passport if you actually remove the map remove the map Atabay passport
then you would see that actually there will be a student ID that would be created in the passport as
well.
So they would be a column in the Student table and they'll be in a column.
There also be a column in the passport for student ID.
So they'll be a column in the Student table for passport I.D. and passport able for today.
And that's not what you would want in typical want to enter relationship in any relationship you would
want.
One of the entities to own the relationship here we would want the student table to contain the passport.
And that's why we have defined it mapped by us.
But the important thing that we would need to make sure is one of the side of the relationship should
be using the fridge.
So I'm trying to figure out what would happen is JPA sees that it's one to one relationship and by default
fecche tape is not lazy Stape is eager.
So it tries and gets the passport details and once it gets the passport details if this is also if the
student mapping is also eager then it can result in a infinite loop kind of situation.
So what we are doing here is we are trying be at making the tape for this particular thing.
So this is how you define one to one relationships how do we find one to many relationship for example
a project and tasked to a project might have multiple tasks that needs to be done.
They took this one to many relationship.
So what we are seeing is project has many tasks.
So we are saying it's on too many relationships for the thing.
They project there'll be multiple desks for the same task master project relationship is many to one
many projects can have one task.
That's the relationship which we are putting in here.
In addition to that what we are doing is we are adding a joined column in the US so in the task column
we are actually adding a join column saying the name of the column should be project underscore.
So in the task table there'll be a column created with the name project and is called ID but you'll
be representing the project that the task is as you see it.
The other thing which we are adding in is something called Mapping a bit similar to the one to one deletion
ship.
So the map debate project.
So we are this is the project that we are referring to in here.
So we are seeing this tasks actually refers to this column Project ID which is apt to project.
So here we are defining up one to many relationship.
So project is related to many sites.
The that kind of relationship is many to many relationship relate to project.
So to date this is defining a many to many relationship between projects instrument a student can be
associated with many projects a project can have multiple solutions.
So I use and at many many to.
In addition to define this stuff when we have a many to many relationship.
Then we would have a relationship table that is created which would have two columns.
Project ID and the student day.
So we would have a project table a student table and a project student table which would contain the
relationship between project and students.
In this video we looked at how to map relationships in G-B Awadallah different kinds of relationship.
One of the examples for them and what are the important tips and tricks related to them and then the
next would you say.