Welcome back in this we do really focus on the Coventry creation behind g.p before we start.
JP application and we get it running.
There's a lot of configuration that you would need to do.
So we'll look at some of the important configuration that you would need to do as part of it.
JP It is those configuration positions or similar configuration configuration you are indeed into the
Manage your factory and transaction manager and also confiscating transaction management.
One of the most important things that you need to understand is we're using spring boot and you're using
spring would be a standard you don't need to do any of the stuff that you'd be talking about in this
piece.
We can we do.
You'll be able to easily do that without configuring all this stuff.
But typically when you're using it with spinning and without using spring boot you'll need to configure
all this stuff.
So let's look at it right now.
One of the important things that you would typically do is define your data source right so you'd need
to define a data source so that you'd be able to connect to the database.
So how do you define the data.
So it is by defining a bean data source and defining the class of Debien that you are using then defining
the driver class you would want to make use of DJT BCU you want to make use of and the user id and password
if you're using JND you don't need to specify the user id and password.
Then we would pick up the JDA you RF and dig the connection details and make use of the connection details
that are configured already on the data.
So what we have here is the values from the property files.
For this specific thing we are connecting to a in-memory database in here.
So we're using a database driver or just google D.B and DUHL is because it's in memory it's Memphis
D.B and the user name and the password for it.
So this is how you create a data set.
If it's Escurial at my school then he had the JTB said right what would be defended.
And you are also a little different.
But other than that the configuration would remain exactly the same.
So the data is what you'd use to connect to a database and how to configure hibernate.
There are a lot of things that you can configure about hibernate so you can just create the hibernate
properties and put it in the resources config for it.
You can configure things like US duelists files which Dallek to use here we are connecting to your screen
so using his disk.
And if you want to format this q as well then you can actually save format skilless Drew and put a Asgill
comment.
So all this kind of stuff you can configure as part of your hibernate properties does how you configure
your hibernate and persistent excitement is used to figure you up assistance you need.
So here we are defining what is the persistence provided that we want to make use of what are the different
dialects and the other stuff that you would want to make use of all those kind of stuff is typically
configured in your position to access it.
The thing is GPL mandates that you would need a persistent criticsm.
And that's the reason why we are creating a persistence or example in here.
So here we are defining a persistence unit got school hype and B how do we configured up and manage
a factory and a transaction manager to configure an entity manage a factory.
You would need a persistence context persistence you need that we have defined it and that's what we
are using in here.
And that data source.
So we're making use of a persistence unit and a data source to create in the main idea factory.
So the entity manager factory is the one which would create the NTD managers for us so if we want to
manage the entities I need entity manager.
How do I get an entity manager the entity managers provided to us by the entity manager.
Actually that's what we are getting in here and what we want to do something we would want to do that
within the boundaries of a transaction.
Right so if I have three steps and if the second step failed I would want to roll back the first step.
That is what transaction management is all about.
So if I am making changes to three tables and the second table change failed then I would want to roll
back everything that is what transaction management is all about and to be able to do this we would
need a transaction main ajor and de-conflict the transaction manager.
We would need an entity manager factory as well as a data source as well.
So this is how we create a bean for a transaction manager in this specific example we're making use
of the JPA transaction manager and we're also using And in addition we want to activate the transaction
management.
Once you've defined the transaction management if you want to make a service transactional or that you
need to do is put an ad transaction or the method which you would want transaction management to be
implemented at.
And so if you do three things in this method then if any of them fail all the earlier ones are also
rolled back and the other way you can use it is by putting an ad transaction on declasse.
Here we are putting it on the method.
You can also put that transactional on demit on the class as well then all the methods in this specific
class would be transactional.
So before you used the method there would be a transaction that is created after all these steps are
successful then done then it would commit the changes if any of these steps failed then it would roll
back all the changes that are done as part of that commit that.
So this is how people can figure out a lot of things related to JBU in this step.
We look at how to define a data source why we use positions that XML how to configure an entity manage
a factory and the transaction manager.
We also look at how to do transaction management for simple spring hibernate integration and build the
next read your way.