Come to this section you get an overview of things related to spring and what we look at in this business
we do want to spring data.
What is the need for it and what is being made.
AJP typically when we want to talk to a entity or to a database in GP what will make use of the entity
manage it and what we'll be creating is something called a depositary.
So in a repository we would write logic like this.
For example here I'm handling the passport object right.
So I would want to save a passport.
And also I would want to create a passport and also get details of the passport from the database.
So this method get passport get the details of the passport from the date of it.
So it does indeed the Madrid manager passport that glass passes the ID gives the passport and it back.
He had to create the passport.
What we are doing here is create passport and passing passport.
And it just calls into the manager MoJ method and we have an persistent persistence context and then
to manage it as something which is defined inside your passport deposit.
Now if you look at the storage repository to save this street in detail it's exactly the same.
The only thing different is student student student student in sort of the passport.
That's the only thing which is different than then that the entire code is exactly the same.
So there's a lot of application in the passport repository and the student repository that's factor
number one the fact that Number two is also the fact that there are there's an explosion of data stores
right.
Earlier the databases were just of one kind or relational databases.
But today there are a lot of other big data.
Data is coming in how do Mongo D.B and a huge Weddady of other apps.
So how do we ensure that the baby talk to data is consistent.
I don't know.
Talk to one data story in one way and to another story not the other way.
And how do I reduce the duplications between the DPA repositories that we've seen here spring data aims
to solve these problems.
It kind of provides a common abstractions to store and retrieve data from data stores.
The most important thing is it is independent of the type of the data stored it does not matter whether
you're talking to a relational database whether you're talking to a big data that is too old or whatever
it is.
Now what does that JPA do is being that AJP extends the concepts of spring data provide a concept called
depositary spring did AJP extends the concept of depositary and pro-white to G.P.A. implementation footed.
So it helps us to use data kind of abstractions to connect to a jeep database so it can do it.
JP How do we use sping data AJP or did we need to do.
Extend is a simple class something like that repository.
So if I want to manage this student entity or that I need to do is say I would want to extend gradually
that the tree the entity I want to manage is student and the primary key is long.
So I just need to create an interface extending the repository interface and I'm really I have created
a strange repository here.
I'm creating a passport repository exactly the same thing that repository passport come along.
Defining the entity to be managed and the primary key of the entity once you do this you'd be able to
exude a lot of methods using decried repository.
Now let's look at couple more a couple more question to how does a repository and why does paging and
sorting repository.
So the important method to represent Indico deposit the RC.
So if I want to update or insert an entity then I would use the same method.
So sical the same method and say save passport.
Look at the passport.
If there's a primary key present then it will update if there is no primary key.
Then we insert a new row and create a new ID for it.
You can do a fine by ID so I can search for a specific ID so I can search for a specific passport based
on its ID.
I can check with an object exists by ID.
I can get all the list so I can get all the entities which represent in it be able to find all you can
delete by ID I can delete a specific thing by ID and I can get count of how many rules are present.
So these are some of the important metadata chapters in the crab repository.
So for the sort of repository you can use all these methods to save this student to update the student
to do it to a student and all that.
And the same thing applies for the passport object as well.
So when we are using the card repository we don't really need to do things like what we were doing earlier.
So we were doing things like this right.
So we needed to do and didn't manage it fine and did it with an entity manager that merge when you define
depositories using something that AJP you don't need to do them anymore.
The repository which is present is paging and sorting repository.
In addition to the basic method which I present in here BGN starting to pro-white sorting and paging
functionalities.
So you'll be able to sort the results on a specific way so you can say I would want to start in descending
order based on this field and then you'd be able to see past what depositary find all based on the star.
So it would get all the rules using this sorting the other thing you can do is to Bejing.
So if I'm getting Todi result I would want to get 10 in each page so I'll get the pages.
So here I'm defending a paid of them and creating a new page request and then passing page bill to the
passport repository.
So what it will do is it will get all the results in its pages of then.
So you can get how many pages are present you can get the next page results and all that kind of stuff
using the paging and sorting repository.
In this way you will get the basics related to spring data what is being data what is the need for it.
What is being that AJP What is the repository and what is paging and sorting repository.
And building studio by.