Welcome back in this you will look at important questions which are related to Aspect Oriented Programming
that really you will start with looking at an important question like What are crosscutting cancers
How do you implement cross-cutting concerns in your application.
If you want to log every request to a web application what are the options you can think of and how
do you crack performance of every request.
What options can you think of those are the different things that we would get.
So let's get started.
A cross-cutting concerns when you talk about web applications.
There are multiple the right web business data integration and other the least each layer specializes
in doing something.
However there are things which are across the.
So for example logging security these are things that you would want to manage across the application
performance management for example.
These are things which are concerns of every of which is present in the application.
And these are called cross-cutting concerns cross-cutting concerns are concerns of all the layers which
are present in an application typically all these cross-cutting consultants are implemented using something
called aspect oriented programming a or b.
For example if you want to log every request that comes to a web application how do I do that.
One of the options that I.
E provide to me is to configure a filter.
Right.
I can configure a filter and then implement a simple method to lob the request and log the response
back.
That's one way or the other way is I can write a or b so I can do some aspect oriented programming saying
I would want to intercept all calls to this controller and before calling any method in this controller
log request and log the response that's what aspect oriented programming would allow us to do even if
I wanted to track the performance of every request even that kind of stuff can also be done using aspect
oriented programming.
Let's now shift our attention towards things like specked foreign Kirt And what are the different types
of AOP that advisors that are present and what is weaving and things like that before we complicate
our minds with any of these things.
Let's look at an eop example right to have a simple hi by servies so I have a third Saibai method and
this is written something.
So these are three method what I want to do is before I call this method on the high by servies I would
want to print the name of the method and I would want to be able to print the different arguments that
are present.
So whenever a method in high school I would want to print its name as well as its arguments.
These are the kind of things that AOP is really good at doing.
So before any of these things is called we'll be able to use AOP to induce recall the name and in the
argument.
How do we do that.
Let's look at an example.
So what we are defining in here is as big.
So we're creating an aspect let's discuss the theory behind this aspect a little later.
So we're creating a spring component and what we are defining in here is something called a point could
what we are saying is high by Sowerby's so high by service any method.
So by start we mean any method is called on the high by servies and any arguments.
What we're saying is before so Ed before means before the method is called.
So you're saying before any method is called on the high by servies what you would need to do is you
need to get the nature of that specific moment.
So get this Diggnation of that method and get its name and also print what arguments are being passed.
So whenever this method any of these methods is called what would happen is these details are printed
to say hi with Wardo value was being passed and the name will be printed out.
So similar to that if it's a controller at let's say this was a control method.
And these are all the different methods in the controller.
So this is before aspect I mean here we are trying to intercept the method call before it happens.
You can also intercept the method call after it happened as well.
What we are seeing after returning so after the metal has completed exec fusion we would want to see
what that is.
He's all here.
We're using it after training and defining a point got too high by so.
So any metal on the base is saying take the result and put it into this object so the result will be
available to us in this object.
So that's why we put reasoning's equal to the cells so the result is made available in here.
So what we're doing in here is at that point that get signature good name.
So you're saying that the method is executed in the name of the mentor as well as what was the research
which was done back what we have said is after the execution of this basic method print the name of
the mental as well as whatever was written back.
So in this case and in this case that nothing will be written back it will be null.
But here high buy would be written and that could be printed out with it or people would be able to
intercept the method calls and do something just before and after as.
The most powerful of the A or B interceptions is what is called round.
So what you can do with an rounded wise.
Here we are implementing and rounded ways.
So what we are doing is simple.
So we have a new method on the high bar so we would want to intercept what we are trying to do in here.
We use a proceeding join point proceeding join point will allow us to proceed on to what we're doing
here is around the method call.
So what happens is just before this method is called just before the method is called the control goes
over to the ground edgewise.
So what happens is we are actually taking this to our game at the start of the third and then we are
saying OK giant point that policy this will make sure that the method is executed.
Whatever method is intercepted that is executed.
The result is returned back and after the completion of the method we are noting the end game and we
are calculating the execution time of that method and printing it out.
That's called and around Edwy.
So somebody is calling this a high.
Third what we'll do is be intercepted before calling them that we are unloading down the time we're
letting it proceed.
And then after that we are not in the time and the difference is the amount of time that was taken to
execute this method.
Imagine if we can do this with a control method or a business method or do you admit that we'll be able
to find the amount of time each of these methods in the previous set of questions we talked about performance
management and we said we can implement that using a or b.
So the best advice to implement that would be in round advice so around sideways is basically you can
do something before the method is executed and you can do something after the method is executed.
What we're doing here is noting down the time of the start of the method and end game of dhimmitude
and then after the method is completed execution and using the difference as the execution time of that
piece we entered using this point good so we can define what the word meant that we would want to intercept
so I can let's say define in sort of the high bar so I can say I would want to intercept all calls to
the data earlier.
Or I can intercept all calls to the business leader.
What we're looking at are code examples which are using aspect G aspect.
JS One of the most famous or P free books here we are intercepting method calls but with AOP actually
you can even intercept changes to values in a field.
So if you have a bean and a bean attribute value has changed or a field value has changed.
Even those kind of things you can find out using aspic cheat in the next week you will get down to the
technical details and identify what are the different things which are present in the examples that
we don't do it.
What is Ajarn point.
What is your advice what is the point Curt.
What is an aspect we ring and leave it until the next to are way.